<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>edmonton on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/edmonton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in edmonton on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/edmonton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>pigeon lake road race 2024</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/pigeonlake2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/pigeonlake2024/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Sundance Beach (Pigeon Lake) Leduc County, Alberta Course: stravalink I hadn&amp;rsquo;t planned on racing Pigeon Lake this year. I&amp;rsquo;d been waiting on my race fee reimbursement before entering the Stieda Classic again, but that came kind of late. A couple of people from my club mentioned that since I&amp;rsquo;m a bit better climber than a big powerful guy, I might find Pigeon Lake more suitable. I debated a bunch, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad I tried it out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>belonging</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240530-belonging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 18:16:56 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240530-belonging/</guid>
      <description>This week I&amp;rsquo;ve had some good rides. There was the Velocity social ride last Saturday in which I risked going with the fast group and I did not die. I was not the fastest in that group and I was working hard, but it went pretty well. It was my second fastest time for 50k.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve been to both the (uncancelled) Fat Tire Tuesday races down in Terwillegar park and have been very slow on my mountain bike.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fat tire tuesday race series</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/ftt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/ftt/</guid>
      <description>Fat Tire Tuesday is a cross-country mountain bike race series in Edmonton. In 2024, all the races are happening at Terwillegar park. The races cost $5 and you can enter in three categories (the fastest do 4 laps, the slower people do 3 laps and the slowest only do 2). There&amp;rsquo;s a point structure and a group on Strava where the news of race results/cancellations happen.&#xA;Further reading of my personal responses with the races can be found under the ftt tag or in my season summaries below:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>terwillegar park</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/terwillegarpark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/terwillegarpark/</guid>
      <description>Terwillegar Park is a park in southwest Edmonton. It has a pile of trails and is a great off-leash area for doggos.&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s a good amount of doubletrack that follows along by the river and countless little ins and out singletrack bits through the trees. One of the downsides of the park is that the soil is very clay-based so it gets super rutty if people ride it before letting it dry out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>spring again</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240425-spring-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 13:26:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240425-spring-again/</guid>
      <description>It is almost the end of April in 2024 and my Strava account says I&amp;rsquo;m in better shape than I was at any point last year. I&amp;rsquo;ve been out for a couple of VCC rides this season where it&amp;rsquo;s been about 11 degrees and I wore my tights and seemed to fit in pretty well.&#xA;In the first week there was a fast group and a slow group, which I definitely knew I should stick with (Strava number notwithstanding).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity cycling club</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/vcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/vcc/</guid>
      <description>Velocity Cycling Club is the group I ride with. There are a few clubs in the Edmonton area that I could have joined. I was going to join ERTC (Edmonton Road and Track Club) back in 2020 but doing things in groups wasn&amp;rsquo;t feasible that year. I ended up with VCC mostly because a couple of the older guys from their club were friendly at a few of my 2022 cyclocross races.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>baby walter cross 2023 - day 2</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-2/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Queen Elizabeth Park Edmonton Course: stravalink I had hoped to do more racing this year, but it turned out that four was what I could handle with my work and other life commitments. So the second day of Baby Walter Cross was my season closer.&#xA;1&#xA;The course this year went the opposite direction of 2022 which I think I preferred. The climbing of the stupid hill was still tough, but the descents weren&amp;rsquo;t terrifying and we got to skip the runup in favour of a singletrack descent (with roots that were highlighted but you needed to dodge).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>baby walter cross 2023 - day 1</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-1/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Queen Elizabeth Park Edmonton Course: stravalink Baby Walter Cross is a two-day race put on by the Alberta Cyclocross Collective, which isn&amp;rsquo;t a club exactly, just all the cx lovers in Edmonton. The park has a really big hill, which makes for a lot of climbing.&#xA;Apparently on the Saturday race (which I didn&amp;rsquo;t attend) there were some big crashes by people trying to bunny-hop the obstacles and failing badly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>school of cross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink Like the previous day&amp;rsquo;s Jim Horner Grand Prix ERTC&amp;rsquo;s School of Cross (p/b Blindman Brewing) 2023 race happened in Capilano Park. The air quality was a bit better on the day so only one race was cancelled (Open Women).&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Elite/Open Men Mark FAGNAN Graham FRANCIS Ryan MCLEAN Expert Men Paulo ALVES 1 Jacob PLAYFAIR Randy PERRY Novice Men Quinten MACKLEM2 Emmett MACKLEM Evan KINDZIERSKI Sport Men Ethan MCGHAN Ryan ARYCHUK Colin WEIR CHABA Sport Women Rachel DUMONT [^3] Kristin BAKER Madeline MAGLEO my results Did not race read more Earned promotion up to Open Men, with his second win (in a row, following JHGP) in Expert.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jim horner grand prix 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink I was so happy this race wasn&amp;rsquo;t taking place in Argyll Park this year. I hated the downhill that someone broke a collarbone on last year and lost so much time on it. Capilano Park was near my house and I could practice on it. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t practice hard enough on wet enough grass, because hoo boy did I not do well on that terrain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>capilano park</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/capilanopark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/capilanopark/</guid>
      <description>Capilano Park is a park in the city of Edmonton, where I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t actually expect a cx race to work, but it does.&#xA;As far as the singletrack in the park goes, this is where you connect up with Goldbar Park and the cool trails in there. I generally prefer riding Eastbound.&#xA;races Jim Horner Grand Prix 2023 School of Cross 2023 Midweek CX Series 2023 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity cross 2023 - smoked out</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Strathcona Science Park Course: stravalink (shared with Tubs on Tubs) Sidney McGill was going to be racing in the Open Men category and I was really excited to see her, and to race in the Novice Men, but by 7am the AQHI was over 10 and no one wanted to get blacklung for a race (also the Alberta Bicycle Association won&amp;rsquo;t let you do anything if the index is over 7).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs supercalifragilisticexpialidocius prestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Strathcona Science Park Course: stravalink Tubs on Tubs Supercalifragilisticexpialidocius Prestige was the race that was going to open up the 2023 ABA CX season. And it did for the Novice Men, Sport Men and Sport Women categories, but sadly, the AQHI hit 11 and the afternoon races had to be cancelled (along with the next day&amp;rsquo;s entire Velocity CX Race).&#xA;But I got my race in, and it was really fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity criterium 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycrit2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycrit2023/</guid>
      <description>Our club put on a criterium and in my effort to try out a few different kinds of racing (despite being a slowpoke) I entered. I rode in the Citizen class again because that&amp;rsquo;s the type of license I got for the season. This time there were three riders instead of two at the Stieda race earlier. The other guys (despite being in Citizen where all genders can enter, we were all dudes) had raced the day before with the iGregari SugarBoddy Criterium, which was on the same course but in the opposite direction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>stieda classic 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2023/</guid>
      <description>We only had two people in my category for this race. The category being Citizen, which is supposed to be a mixed gender, less intense beginner kind of racing. The other guy, Keith, was also part of my cycling club but he said he was only in this class by mistake. He was confused and could probably have been in the Mens&amp;rsquo; Category 4. But there we were.&#xA;We got to start with the Women Cat 4 group which was awesome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>zombie baby walter cross 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2022/</guid>
      <description>I was the last competitor across the line in the Novice class of the Zombie Baby Walter Cross race. But a bunch of people had been lapped or did not finish, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually in last place. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how that feels.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not so funny how it feels to wipe out trying to turn while sliding down a grassy hill. Which I did. But I kept going, gritting my teeth while kids in my race were bunny-hopping the barriers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs superduper prestige 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2022/</guid>
      <description>I returned to cyclocross in 2022, and went back to the same race in the same park. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that makes this a classic or not.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d tested this course beforehand. My house is just across the river from the &amp;ldquo;indestructible Strathcona Science Park&amp;rdquo;1 so this was where I&amp;rsquo;d been riding up and down hills and practicing my off-cambers the week before.&#xA;2&#xA;In the tech guide the organizers had released it looked like the really super-steep downhill I&amp;rsquo;d wiped out on in my practice laps back in 2019 was not part of the course, which I appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>strathcona science park</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/strathconasciencepark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/strathconasciencepark/</guid>
      <description>Strathcona Science Park is a provincial park just outside Edmonton. It&amp;rsquo;s rutted and full of gopher holes and apparently has toxic seepage in places. There&amp;rsquo;s no sandy area but it does have a big downhill with long stairs for a runup.&#xA;This is my &amp;ldquo;home course&amp;rdquo; because I used to live just across the river, so it&amp;rsquo;s a convenient place to practice my cx race techniques, do laps to build my stamina and just generally rip around.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>stieda classic 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2022/</guid>
      <description>My knee went pop in the last 7km of the ride and Mike who I&amp;rsquo;d been riding with left me behind. It was all right though. I was going to finish my first road race. And yes, I was slow, but that was okay.&#xA;results 43rd place (out of 50 in Category 5)&#xA;Average Speed 27.72 km/h&#xA;2:03:22 (2 Laps) 33:59 behind winner&#xA;Lap 1 49:32 Lap 2 1:13:49 (note that this lap was longer) Zone 4 Results</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>edmonton and legends of exile</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/180824-feanor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 15:37:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/180824-feanor/</guid>
      <description>The smoke from wildfires has been darkening our skies in Edmonton, and I realized when biking between the flames of the Suncor refineries that the grim brown greyness, the miasma of grit, this is what it feels like to live in Edmonton compared to Nanaimo. It isn&amp;rsquo;t always so externalized but even on the days when the sky is clear this is a foul place to be exiled.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m reading The Silmarillion these days and I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize how much I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s elves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>heading east for sunsets and seasons</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/161028-eastward/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 02:20:36 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/161028-eastward/</guid>
      <description>In followup to the last post, yes, I did enjoy Nanaimo more than Campbell River. But now it&amp;rsquo;s time to be moving again. My partner and I are headed to Edmonton to start new jobs on November 7th. It&amp;rsquo;s a return to the prairies for me and I think I&amp;rsquo;ll like it better than I did when last I lived in Winnipeg.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my 30s out on the west coast and I do like the mildness of the winters here.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
