<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>road on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/road/</link>
    <description>Recent content in road on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/road/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>stieda classic 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2023/</guid>
      <description>We only had two people in my category for this race. The category being Citizen, which is supposed to be a mixed gender, less intense beginner kind of racing. The other guy, Keith, was also part of my cycling club but he said he was only in this class by mistake. He was confused and could probably have been in the Mens&amp;rsquo; Category 4. But there we were.&#xA;We got to start with the Women Cat 4 group which was awesome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bike racing season 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/season2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/season2022/</guid>
      <description>I rode cyclocross races in 2022 but they didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like cyclocross. They aren&amp;rsquo;t muddy and cold1. Part of that was due to the boiling frog that we are as a planet but part of that is due to living in Edmonton, where we don&amp;rsquo;t really get shoulder seasons. The abrupt floompf of winter that happened on November 2 starts fatbike season, not a time for racing in mud, like in Europe (or even Victoria, which is where the Canadian nationals are going to be happening in November).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>stieda classic 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2022/</guid>
      <description>My knee went pop in the last 7km of the ride and Mike who I&amp;rsquo;d been riding with left me behind. It was all right though. I was going to finish my first road race. And yes, I was slow, but that was okay.&#xA;results 43rd place (out of 50 in Category 5)&#xA;Average Speed 27.72 km/h&#xA;2:03:22 (2 Laps) 33:59 behind winner&#xA;Lap 1 49:32 Lap 2 1:13:49 (note that this lap was longer) Zone 4 Results</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
