<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ertc on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/ertc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ertc on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/ertc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>pigeon lake road race 2024</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/pigeonlake2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/pigeonlake2024/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Sundance Beach (Pigeon Lake) Leduc County, Alberta Course: stravalink I hadn&amp;rsquo;t planned on racing Pigeon Lake this year. I&amp;rsquo;d been waiting on my race fee reimbursement before entering the Stieda Classic again, but that came kind of late. A couple of people from my club mentioned that since I&amp;rsquo;m a bit better climber than a big powerful guy, I might find Pigeon Lake more suitable. I debated a bunch, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad I tried it out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>school of cross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink Like the previous day&amp;rsquo;s Jim Horner Grand Prix ERTC&amp;rsquo;s School of Cross (p/b Blindman Brewing) 2023 race happened in Capilano Park. The air quality was a bit better on the day so only one race was cancelled (Open Women).&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Open Men Mark FAGNAN Graham FRANCIS Ryan MCLEAN Expert Men Paulo ALVES 1 Jacob PLAYFAIR Randy PERRY Sport Women Rachel DUMONT [^3] Kristin BAKER Madeline MAGLEO Sport Men Ethan MCGHAN Ryan ARYCHUK Colin WEIR CHABA Novice Men Quinten MACKLEM2 Emmett MACKLEM Evan KINDZIERSKI my results Did not race read more Earned promotion up to Open Men, with his second win (in a row, following JHGP) in Expert.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
