<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>training on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/training/</link>
    <description>Recent content in training on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 23:01:12 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>back on the bike</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/240126-back-on-the-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 11:19:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/240126-back-on-the-bike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m riding my bike again. It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months off dealing with some other issues, but I&amp;rsquo;m making my legs go &amp;lsquo;round in circles again. The big difference compared with last winter is that I&amp;rsquo;m riding indoors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got a Wahoo smart trainer in fall when the &lt;a href=&#34;../../tags/cx/&#34;&gt;cyclocross&lt;/a&gt; season was getting smoked out and it was dangerous to go outside and breathe heavily. It was heavily on sale because it isn&amp;rsquo;t a full-on smart trainer that replaces your rear wheel and has a computer out front built in. It&amp;rsquo;s the kind that rolls against your rear tire&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/231017-scars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/231017-scars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my first cyclocross race I was riding around afterwards and hit a pothole in &lt;a href=&#34;../strathconasciencepark/&#34;&gt;Strathcona Science Park&lt;/a&gt; whacking my right ankle on my pedal and gouging a chunk out of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Training for my 2023 cx season I slipped my right foot and gouged my ankle on my big ring. This one probably could have used stitches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Half a week before entering the &lt;a href=&#34;../hopnhurl2023/&#34;&gt;Hop n Hurl race&lt;/a&gt; I was cruising downhill to &lt;a href=&#34;../capilanopark/&#34;&gt;Capilano Park&lt;/a&gt; for some good cx practice. The offroad downhill goes into Rundle park and is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trailforks.com/trails/get-ready-to-rundle-60390/&#34;&gt;get ready to rundle&lt;/a&gt; on TrailForks. I was descending on the hoods, not in the drops and I guess my weight wasn&amp;rsquo;t far enough back so when I hit the hard rut and my front wheel turned I went over the bars. I didn&amp;rsquo;t hit my head but got my knees, hip, wrist and ribs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hardcore hop n hurl 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/races/hopnhurl2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/races/hopnhurl2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#39;book-hint &#39;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.albertabicycle.ab.ca/uploads/files/Hop%20%26%20Hurl%202023.pdf&#34;&gt;Tech Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&#34;../voyageurpark/&#34;&gt;Voyageur Park&lt;/a&gt; Devon&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Course: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/segments/35564994&#34;&gt;stravalink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I came into this race knowing that last year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../puncheurcross2022/&#34;&gt;Puncheur Cross&lt;/a&gt; was my favourite. Unfortunately I had &lt;a href=&#34;../231017-scars/&#34;&gt;a training crash&lt;/a&gt; the Tuesday before this race, which put me in kind of a bad place. Mostly scraped up, but also a bit of a bruised wrist and some bruised ribs. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d be okay to race still, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t setting my expectations too high.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>embrace the suck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/230919-embrace-the-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/230919-embrace-the-suck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Embrace the suck&amp;rdquo;[^1]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href=&#34;../cx/&#34;&gt;cx&lt;/a&gt; rider this ethos means a lot. In cross you&amp;rsquo;re often racing in bad weather, cold weather, slippery weather. The courses are designed to make it hard for you to go quickly, not like a road bike race. All the twists and turns and lack of traction can make it so the fast people don&amp;rsquo;t get to use their speed, and craftiness, technique comes to the fore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>midweek racing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/races/wnw2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/races/wnw2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my &lt;a href=&#34;../230829-prepping-a-season/&#34;&gt;season preparations&lt;/a&gt; I decided to at least try the midweek &lt;a href=&#34;../cx/&#34;&gt;cx&lt;/a&gt; racing that goes on in Edmonton. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird because it&amp;rsquo;s so casual and hard to find information about. There are people asking questions in the Alberta CX Facebook group and you get a response with a screenshot from somewhere(?) giving a schedule. It seems that the people who know, know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And holy crap did a lot of people know about it last night!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>preparing for a season</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/230829-prepping-a-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/230829-prepping-a-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Alberta Bicycle Association Cyclo-cross Cup begins this weekend with the &lt;a href=&#34;../tubsontubs2023/&#34;&gt;Tubs on Tubs&lt;/a&gt; race and the &lt;a href=&#34;../velocitycross2023/&#34;&gt;Velocity CX&lt;/a&gt; and I am excited.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These races take place at &lt;a href=&#34;../strathconasciencepark&#34;&gt;Strathcona Science Park&lt;/a&gt;, which is a five minute ride from my house, so it&amp;rsquo;s my closest thing to a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; race and where I do most of my ripping around on grass to practice &amp;lsquo;crossing. The other day I was out there and saw someone else also riding around on the grass and flagged her down. Turned out she was one of the race organizers planning out the course.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>go team optimism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/230530-coaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/230530-coaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I joined &lt;a href=&#34;../vcc/&#34;&gt;a cycling club&lt;/a&gt; in 2023 and we have a coach. I have never had a coach before. I haven&amp;rsquo;t ever really done sports so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what a coach is supposed to do. But Kevin seems earnest and nice and is trying so hard to be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before this season&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../stiedaclassic2023/&#34;&gt;first race&lt;/a&gt; he held a racers&amp;rsquo; meeting to go over the course using veloviewer and to talk about tactics and what we should be doing before a race. I was at work that night, so I asked if he&amp;rsquo;d be able to record it and he did. He talked about wind directions and planning and prep and where to attack the group if we had the legs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
