<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cx on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/cx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cx on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/cx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>cyclocross</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/bike/cx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/bike/cx/</guid>
      <description>You ride around in a field and sometimes have to get off your bike and carry it. It&amp;rsquo;s awesome.&#xA;Read more about my experiences with cyclocross in those posts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bike race list</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/bike/race/racelist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/bike/race/racelist/</guid>
      <description>I write reports about races I ride in&#xA;Stieda Classic </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>baby walter cross 2023 - day 2</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-2/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Queen Elizabeth Park Edmonton&#xA;Course: stravalink&#xA;I had hoped to do more racing this year, but it turned out that four was what I could handle with my work and other life commitments. So the second day of Baby Walter Cross was my season closer.&#xA;The course this year went the opposite direction of 2022 which I think I preferred. The climbing of the stupid hill was still tough, but the descents weren&amp;rsquo;t terrifying and we got to skip the runup in favour of a singletrack descent (with roots that were highlighted but you needed to dodge).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>baby walter cross 2023 - day 1</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-1/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Queen Elizabeth Park Edmonton&#xA;Course: stravalink&#xA;Baby Walter Cross is a two-day race put on by the Alberta Cyclocross Collective, which isn&amp;rsquo;t a club exactly, just all the cx lovers in Edmonton. The park has a really big hill, which makes for a lot of climbing.&#xA;Apparently on the Saturday race (which I didn&amp;rsquo;t attend) there were some big crashes by people trying to bunny-hop the obstacles and failing badly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hardcore hop n hurl 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/hopnhurl2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/hopnhurl2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Voyageur Park Devon&#xA;Course: stravalink&#xA;I came into this race knowing that last year&amp;rsquo;s Puncheur Cross was my favourite. Unfortunately I had a training crash the Tuesday before this race, which put me in kind of a bad place. Mostly scraped up, but also a bit of a bruised wrist and some bruised ribs. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d be okay to race still, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t setting my expectations too high.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>drie zussen superprestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</guid>
      <description> Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Canmore Nordic Centre Canmore&#xA;Course: stravalink&#xA;ABA Cup race. Construction on the course. Looked beautiful in the mountains. This is where I&amp;rsquo;d like to go for a travelling race next year.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Open Women Christiane BILODEAU Nico KNOLL Kelsey DUFFIELD Open Men Mark FAGNAN Finn BORSTMAYER Eric BERG Expert Men Jacob PLAYFAIR Larix HALLETT Brett GREINER Novice Men Petr HOLUB Mitchell ROBERTS Emmett MACKLEM Sport Men Patrick MCCRADY Nigel BAINES Sean SWEENEY Sport Women Lydia STACK-MICHASIW Daena SIDNEY Kathryn SWEENEY my results Did not race read more bike stuff </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>puncheur cross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/puncheurcross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/puncheurcross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Voyageur Park Devon&#xA;Course: stravalink&#xA;This was Provincials for this year, which seems early.&#xA;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t at this race, but Nancy St-Hilaire has good pictures on her SmugMug.&#xA;results Official Results CrossResults Podia Open Women Jenaya FRANCIS Nico KNOLL Christiane BILODEAU Open Men Eric BERG Ryan MACLEAN 1 Andrew DAVIDSON Junior Women Dakota DIXON U17 Women Madeline MAGLEO Lily GORDON U15 Women Hazel ROBERTS Sarah WELSH Eliza MCRAE Junior Men Graham FRANCIS Colton ZABOLOTNEY Ben MORIN U17 Men Larix HALLET Quinten MACKLEM Liam BATE U15 Men William KINDZIERSKI Finlay ROBERTS Riley OOSTERHOF Master Women 35-44 Bridget LINDER Jenn PROCHE Kristin BAKER Master Women 45+ Jay SMITH Michelle JACKMAN Daena SIDNEY Master Men 35-44 Graham DIEHL Blaine SHERMAN Adam ROBERTS Master Men 45-54 Paul MARTIN Randy PERRY David ROBERTS Master Men 55-64 Ed GARVIN Robert MARTENS Peter LAWRENCE Master Men 65+ Ken GERMAINE Gregory PATYCHUK Louis BUGEAUD Sport Women Alina CUSTODIO Leanne ERIKSON Alyssa BARKER Novice Men Emmett MACKLEM Jett FENTON Arun WARD my results Did not race read more My 2022 Experience at Puncheur Cross Only a 14 second gap between first and second for Provincial champion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>western cyclocross challenge 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</guid>
      <description> Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Canmore Nordic Centre Canmore&#xA;Course: stravalink&#xA;Western Challenge CX. This race is done in age groups to get points for call-ups for Nationals and what have you.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Elite/Open Women Ella MYERS Christiane BILODEAU Francesca SEAL Junior Women Nico KNOLL Maria MCCARTNEY Keely HAMILTON U15 Women Hazel ROBERTS Eliza MCRAE U17 Women Lydia STACK-MICHASIW Brooke BATES Ella EIDSVIK Elite/Open Men Eric BERG Ryan MACLEAN Manu MOORE U15 Men James CHALKLEY William KINDZIERSKI Finlay ROBERTS U17 Men Ethan WOOD Larix HALLETT Quinten MACKLEM Masters Men 35-44 Andrew DAVIDSON Graham DIEHL Jesse BAUER Masters Men 45-54 Mark KNOLL Paul MARTIN David ROBERTS Masters Men 55-64 Ed GARVIN Peter LAWRENCE Robert MARTENS Masters Men 65+ Gregory PATYCHUK Ken GERMAINE John ATTO Masters Women 35-44 Pepper HARLTON Bridget LINDER Jenn PROCHE Masters Women 45-54 Susanne MCARTHUR Shantel KOENIG Shawna DONALDSON Masters Women 55-64 Rachel DUMONT Junior Men Ben MORIN Colton ZABOLOTNEY Rhett BATES my results Did not race read more </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>school of cross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Capilano Park Edmonton&#xA;Course: stravalink&#xA;Like the previous day&amp;rsquo;s Jim Horner Grand Prix ERTC&amp;rsquo;s School of Cross (p/b Blindman Brewing) 2023 race happened in Capilano Park. The air quality was a bit better on the day so only one race was cancelled (Open Women).&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Elite/Open Men Mark FAGNAN Graham FRANCIS Ryan MCLEAN Expert Men Paulo ALVES 1 Jacob PLAYFAIR Randy PERRY Novice Men Quinten MACKLEM2 Emmett MACKLEM Evan KINDZIERSKI Sport Men Ethan MCGHAN Ryan ARYCHUK Colin WEIR CHABA Sport Women Rachel DUMONT [^3] Kristin BAKER Madeline MAGLEO my results Did not race read more Earned promotion up to Open Men, with his second win (in a row, following JHGP) in Expert.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jim horner grand prix 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Capilano Park Edmonton&#xA;Course: stravalink&#xA;I was so happy this race wasn&amp;rsquo;t taking place in Argyll Park this year. I hated the downhill that someone broke a collarbone on last year and lost so much time on it. Capilano Park was near my house and I could practice on it. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t practice hard enough on wet enough grass, because hoo boy did I not do well on that terrain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>capilano park</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/bike/capilanopark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/bike/capilanopark/</guid>
      <description>Capilano Park is a park in the city of Edmonton, where I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t actually expect a cx race to work, but it does.&#xA;As far as the singletrack in the park goes, this is where you connect up with Goldbar Park and the cool trails in there. I generally prefer riding Eastbound.&#xA;races Jim Horner Grand Prix 2023 School of Cross 2023 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the real diehl cyclocross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/peloton2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/peloton2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Canadian Southern Baptist Seminary - Cochrane&#xA;Course: stravalink&#xA;&amp;ldquo;The Real Diehl&amp;rdquo; Cyclocross&#xA;Peloton&amp;rsquo;s first CX race they&amp;rsquo;ve put on. Swag included a UCI tire checker.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Scott DESMARAIS Spencer POOTZ Larix HALLETT1 Novice Men Joel DYCK William LEMIEUX Douglas GRAY Open Men Andrew DAVIDSON Shawn BUNNIN Mark KNOLL Open Women Pepper HARLTON Kelsey DUFFIELD Nico KNOLL Sport Men Nigel BAINES Robert MARTENS Garth STOTTS Sport Women Alina CUSTODIO Hazel ROBERTS Elané FERGUSON my results Did not race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>deadgoat supercross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/deadgoat2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/deadgoat2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Canadian Southern Baptist Seminary - Cochrane&#xA;Course: stravalink1&#xA;It looks like this was a hot and windy race.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Scott DESMARAIS Emile VOGEL-NAKAMURA Spencer POOTZ Novice Men Joel DYCK Karol SIARKA Quinten MACKLEM Open Men Andrew DAVIDSON Shawn BUNNIN Mark KNOLL Open Women Sidney MCGILL Ella MYERS Nico KNOLL Sport Men Larix HALLETT Patrick MCCRADY Nigel BAINES Sport Women Avree COLLING Hazel ROBERTS Hilary BUCKLEY my results Did not race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity cross 2023 - smoked out</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Strathcona Science Park&#xA;Course: stravalink (shared with Tubs on Tubs)&#xA;Sidney McGill was going to be racing in the Open Men category and I was really excited to see her, and to race in the Novice Men, but by 7am the AQHI was over 10 and no one wanted to get blacklung for a race (also the Alberta Bicycle Association won&amp;rsquo;t let you do anything if the index is over 7).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs supercalifragilisticexpialidocius prestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide&#xA;Location: Strathcona Science Park&#xA;Course: stravalink&#xA;Tubs on Tubs Supercalifragilisticexpialidocius Prestige was the race that was going to open up the 2023 ABA CX season. And it did for the Novice Men, Sport Men and Sport Women categories, but sadly, the AQHI hit 11 and the afternoon races had to be cancelled (along with the next day&amp;rsquo;s entire Velocity CX Race).&#xA;But I got my race in, and it was really fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>zombie baby walter cross 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2022/</guid>
      <description>I was the last competitor across the line in the Novice class of the Zombie Baby Walter Cross race. But a bunch of people had been lapped or did not finish, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually in last place. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how that feels.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not so funny how it feels to wipe out trying to turn while sliding down a grassy hill. Which I did. But I kept going, gritting my teeth while kids in my race were bunny-hopping the barriers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>puncheur cross 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/puncheurcross2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/puncheurcross2022/</guid>
      <description>I loved the Devon Puncheur race. I also love that it got a writeup entitled The Best Grassroots Cyclocross Race You&amp;rsquo;ve Never Heard of1 I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been to Devon, which is just southwest of Edmonton, before this race, but Voyageur Park was a really nice example of this region&amp;rsquo;s river valley terrain. The course went through the trees, around a flat corkscrew feature, down by the river and was my introduction to sand on a &amp;lsquo;cross course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jim horner grand prix 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2022/</guid>
      <description>My second race of the 2022 cyclocross season was presented by the Juventus Cycling Club at the Argyll Velodrome. Not in the velodrome itself, but the park surrounding it. When I was looking at the map in the preceding days I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure where the ups and downs and how it would work as a course. There was a toboggan hill. Were we going to have to up that? Down it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs superduper prestige 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2022/</guid>
      <description>I returned to cyclocross in 2022, and went back to the same race in the same park. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that makes this a classic or not.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d tested this course beforehand. My house is just across the river from the &amp;ldquo;indestructible Strathcona Science Park&amp;rdquo;1 so this was where I&amp;rsquo;d been riding up and down hills and practicing my off-cambers the week before (see my idyllic practice image).&#xA;In the tech guide the organizers had released it looked like the really super-steep downhill I&amp;rsquo;d wiped out on in my practice laps back in 2019 was not part of the course, which I appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>strathcona science park</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/bike/strathconasciencepark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/bike/strathconasciencepark/</guid>
      <description>Strathcona Science Park is a provincial park just outside Edmonton. It&amp;rsquo;s rutted and full of gopher holes and apparently has toxic seepage in places. There&amp;rsquo;s no sandy area but it does have a big downhill with long stairs for a runup.&#xA;This is my &amp;ldquo;home course&amp;rdquo; because I used to live just across the river, so it&amp;rsquo;s a convenient place to practice my cx race techniques, do laps to build my stamina and just generally rip around.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
