<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 15:19:03 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>heading east for sunsets and seasons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/161028-eastward/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 02:20:36 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/161028-eastward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In followup to the last post, yes, I did enjoy Nanaimo more than Campbell River. But now it&amp;rsquo;s time to be moving again. My partner and I are headed to Edmonton to start new jobs on November 7th. It&amp;rsquo;s a return to the prairies for me and I think I&amp;rsquo;ll like it better than I did when last I lived in Winnipeg.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my 30s out on the west coast and I do like the mildness of the winters here. But maybe it&amp;rsquo;s okay to live somewhere a little harder to deal with. A little (lot) colder, but with better food (non-sushi division). The new job should be much better than working for my former employer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mobility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/140831-mobility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 05:36:49 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/140831-mobility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I finish my month-long move down to Nanaimo for &lt;a href=&#34;http://librarianaut.wordpress.com/2014/08/25/not-quite-a-comeback/&#34;&gt;my new job&lt;/a&gt;. By this time next week though, I&amp;rsquo;ll be on vacation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope I like Nanaimo better than Campbell River. I feel kind of bad for not liking it here. There are some very nice people in this town, but nothing ever really clicked for me. I will miss the folks from Coho Books.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Nanaimo there are comic and game shops I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to bike to. The ferry to Vancouver is way closer and easier. I know a bunch of people there already (yes, most of them are librarians) so maybe I won&amp;rsquo;t have to live on the internet quite so much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
