<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>club on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/club/</link>
    <description>Recent content in club on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 18:16:56 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/club/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>belonging</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240530-belonging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 18:16:56 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240530-belonging/</guid>
      <description>This week I&amp;rsquo;ve had some good rides. There was the Velocity social ride last Saturday in which I risked going with the fast group and I did not die. I was not the fastest in that group and I was working hard, but it went pretty well. It was my second fastest time for 50k.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve been to both the (uncancelled) Fat Tire Tuesday races down in Terwillegar park and have been very slow on my mountain bike.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>spring again</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240425-spring-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 13:26:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240425-spring-again/</guid>
      <description>It is almost the end of April in 2024 and my Strava account says I&amp;rsquo;m in better shape than I was at any point last year. I&amp;rsquo;ve been out for a couple of VCC rides this season where it&amp;rsquo;s been about 11 degrees and I wore my tights and seemed to fit in pretty well.&#xA;In the first week there was a fast group and a slow group, which I definitely knew I should stick with (Strava number notwithstanding).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity cycling club</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/vcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/vcc/</guid>
      <description>Velocity Cycling Club is the group I ride with. There are a few clubs in the Edmonton area that I could have joined. I was going to join ERTC (Edmonton Road and Track Club) back in 2020 but doing things in groups wasn&amp;rsquo;t feasible that year. I ended up with VCC mostly because a couple of the older guys from their club were friendly at a few of my 2022 cyclocross races.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
