<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>race reports on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/race-reports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in race reports on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/race-reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>jim horner grand prix 2024</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2024/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink 1&#xA;The Jim Horner Grand Prix of Cyclo-cross was my first Edmonton race of the season, and it went well. Unlike last year we had clear skies with no Air Quality warnings so all the races happened.&#xA;Being in Novice Men, I had an early start while the grass was still dewy and wet. The course opened with a bunch of twisty turns including an uphill off-camber thing (see the picture above of the Sport Men tackling it).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the range gravel race 2024</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/range2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/range2024/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Claresholm, Alberta Course: ridewithgpslink Back when I was thinking about the bike riding I wanted to do this year, a gravel event was on my mind. The idea with a gravel race is it&amp;rsquo;s a long route on dirt roads away from traffic. There&amp;rsquo;s a mass start and though there are fast people &amp;ldquo;racing&amp;rdquo; the event there will be far more just out there doing the ride, trying to finish and have a good time1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pigeon lake road race 2024</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/pigeonlake2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/pigeonlake2024/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Sundance Beach (Pigeon Lake) Leduc County, Alberta Course: stravalink I hadn&amp;rsquo;t planned on racing Pigeon Lake this year. I&amp;rsquo;d been waiting on my race fee reimbursement before entering the Stieda Classic again, but that came kind of late. A couple of people from my club mentioned that since I&amp;rsquo;m a bit better climber than a big powerful guy, I might find Pigeon Lake more suitable. I debated a bunch, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad I tried it out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>baby walter cross 2023 - day 2</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-2/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Queen Elizabeth Park Edmonton Course: stravalink I had hoped to do more racing this year, but it turned out that four was what I could handle with my work and other life commitments. So the second day of Baby Walter Cross was my season closer.&#xA;1&#xA;The course this year went the opposite direction of 2022 which I think I preferred. The climbing of the stupid hill was still tough, but the descents weren&amp;rsquo;t terrifying and we got to skip the runup in favour of a singletrack descent (with roots that were highlighted but you needed to dodge).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hardcore hop n hurl 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/hopnhurl2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/hopnhurl2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Voyageur Park Devon Course: stravalink I came into this race knowing that last year&amp;rsquo;s Puncheur Cross was my favourite. Unfortunately I had a training crash the Tuesday before this race, which put me in kind of a bad place. Mostly scraped up, but also a bit of a bruised wrist and some bruised ribs. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d be okay to race still, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t setting my expectations too high.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jim horner grand prix 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink I was so happy this race wasn&amp;rsquo;t taking place in Argyll Park this year. I hated the downhill that someone broke a collarbone on last year and lost so much time on it. Capilano Park was near my house and I could practice on it. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t practice hard enough on wet enough grass, because hoo boy did I not do well on that terrain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs supercalifragilisticexpialidocius prestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Strathcona Science Park Course: stravalink Tubs on Tubs Supercalifragilisticexpialidocius Prestige was the race that was going to open up the 2023 ABA CX season. And it did for the Novice Men, Sport Men and Sport Women categories, but sadly, the AQHI hit 11 and the afternoon races had to be cancelled (along with the next day&amp;rsquo;s entire Velocity CX Race).&#xA;But I got my race in, and it was really fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity criterium 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycrit2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycrit2023/</guid>
      <description>Our club put on a criterium and in my effort to try out a few different kinds of racing (despite being a slowpoke) I entered. I rode in the Citizen class again because that&amp;rsquo;s the type of license I got for the season. This time there were three riders instead of two at the Stieda race earlier. The other guys (despite being in Citizen where all genders can enter, we were all dudes) had raced the day before with the iGregari SugarBoddy Criterium, which was on the same course but in the opposite direction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>stieda classic 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2023/</guid>
      <description>We only had two people in my category for this race. The category being Citizen, which is supposed to be a mixed gender, less intense beginner kind of racing. The other guy, Keith, was also part of my cycling club but he said he was only in this class by mistake. He was confused and could probably have been in the Mens&amp;rsquo; Category 4. But there we were.&#xA;We got to start with the Women Cat 4 group which was awesome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>zombie baby walter cross 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2022/</guid>
      <description>I was the last competitor across the line in the Novice class of the Zombie Baby Walter Cross race. But a bunch of people had been lapped or did not finish, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually in last place. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how that feels.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not so funny how it feels to wipe out trying to turn while sliding down a grassy hill. Which I did. But I kept going, gritting my teeth while kids in my race were bunny-hopping the barriers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>puncheur cross 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/puncheurcross2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/puncheurcross2022/</guid>
      <description>I loved the Devon Puncheur race. I also love that it got a writeup entitled The Best Grassroots Cyclocross Race You&amp;rsquo;ve Never Heard of1 I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been to Devon, which is just southwest of Edmonton, before this race, but Voyageur Park was a really nice example of this region&amp;rsquo;s river valley terrain. The course went through the trees, around a flat corkscrew feature, down by the river and was my introduction to sand on a &amp;lsquo;cross course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jim horner grand prix 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2022/</guid>
      <description>My second race of the 2022 cyclocross season was presented by the Juventus Cycling Club at the Argyll Velodrome. Not in the velodrome itself, but the park surrounding it. When I was looking at the map in the preceding days I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure where the ups and downs and how it would work as a course. There was a toboggan hill. Were we going to have to up that? Down it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs superduper prestige 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2022/</guid>
      <description>I returned to cyclocross in 2022, and went back to the same race in the same park. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that makes this a classic or not.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d tested this course beforehand. My house is just across the river from the &amp;ldquo;indestructible Strathcona Science Park&amp;rdquo;1 so this was where I&amp;rsquo;d been riding up and down hills and practicing my off-cambers the week before.&#xA;2&#xA;In the tech guide the organizers had released it looked like the really super-steep downhill I&amp;rsquo;d wiped out on in my practice laps back in 2019 was not part of the course, which I appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>stieda classic 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2022/</guid>
      <description>My knee went pop in the last 7km of the ride and Mike who I&amp;rsquo;d been riding with left me behind. It was all right though. I was going to finish my first road race. And yes, I was slow, but that was okay.&#xA;results 43rd place (out of 50 in Category 5)&#xA;Average Speed 27.72 km/h&#xA;2:03:22 (2 Laps) 33:59 behind winner&#xA;Lap 1 49:32 Lap 2 1:13:49 (note that this lap was longer) Zone 4 Results</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
