<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>my 2025 cx season summary</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twentytwentyfive was a short &amp;lsquo;cross season in Alberta. We were down a couple of ABA Cup races in Edmonton (no &lt;a href=&#34;../../races/tubs2024/&#34;&gt;Tubs on Tubs&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;../../races/velocity2024/&#34;&gt;Velocity CX&lt;/a&gt;), the Canmore races were cancelled, and provincials were early and it all felt a little lessened.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday-worlds&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  Wednesday Worlds&#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#wednesday-worlds&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year I thought ahead and planned out my &amp;lsquo;cross seaon at work so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to miss any of the Wednesday Worlds&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; nights. I just like them for the camaraderie and the feeling that I am part of a community of weirdos riding around too hard in an inefficient manner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>before cross comes</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/250821-before-cross-comes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 12:58:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/250821-before-cross-comes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The summer is almost done and I haven&amp;rsquo;t updated this site in ages. But that is okay. I&amp;rsquo;m fine with not having written. Really and truly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year I haven&amp;rsquo;t biked as much as I did last year. Part of that is because I&amp;rsquo;ve started volunteering once a week at &lt;a href=&#34;https://bikeedmonton.ca/&#34;&gt;Bike Edmonton&lt;/a&gt;, which takes up time. Part of it is just being tired, and demoralized for being slow. I took up the mantle of Mountain Bike representative for &lt;a href=&#34;VCC.md&#34;&gt;VCC&lt;/a&gt; which meant I missed a few &lt;a href=&#34;ftt.md&#34;&gt;ftt&lt;/a&gt; races riding alone in &lt;a href=&#34;capilanopark.md&#34;&gt;capilanopark&lt;/a&gt; instead. When I did get in a couple of races, I was oh so slow, even though I worked so hard. I didn&amp;rsquo;t make it out to the good mountain biking at all this summer. I didn&amp;rsquo;t ride to work as much as I wanted. Just generally a blah kind of year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>thinking about 64 squares</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/250131-64squares/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 09:34:14 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/250131-64squares/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to focus a bit this past year. When I come home to a quiet house (four days a week) there are many things I could do. Watch shows, read books, cook interesting meals, go out and spend money being around people. But when I have all those options the tendency I have is to just kind of waste it. To work on that I&amp;rsquo;ve got three main things I&amp;rsquo;m working on filling my time with: bikes, books, and chess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>my 2024 cx season summary</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cyclocross season starts in September for us in Edmonton. Some years we&amp;rsquo;ve (apparently) had snow right for the first races. There are kind of three aspects to the season for me. A bunch of training, the casual races and the sanctioned Alberta Cup races.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Training is training. I ride up and down hills and in parks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday-night-worlds&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  Wednesday Night Worlds&#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#wednesday-night-worlds&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much like the &lt;a href=&#34;../ftt/&#34;&gt;Fat Tire Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; races, Edmonton has a series of $5 cx races in &amp;lsquo;cross season. The A group starts a minute before the B group which starts a minute before the C group and everyone races for about 25 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>belonging</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240530-belonging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 18:16:56 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240530-belonging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I&amp;rsquo;ve had some good rides. There was the &lt;a href=&#34;../vcc/&#34;&gt;Velocity&lt;/a&gt; social ride last Saturday in which I risked going with the fast group and I did not die. I was not the fastest in that group and I was working hard, but it went pretty well. It was my second fastest time for 50k.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been to both the (uncancelled) &lt;a href=&#34;../ftt/&#34;&gt;Fat Tire Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; races down in &lt;a href=&#34;../terwillegarpark/&#34;&gt;Terwillegar park&lt;/a&gt; and have been very slow on my mountain bike. I do tend to prefer riding that bike for the joy of movement rather than pushing pushing pushing myself, but it&amp;rsquo;s a good non-comfort-zone kind of experience. And getting smoked by teenagers gives me good practice for the &lt;a href=&#34;../cx/&#34;&gt;cyclocross&lt;/a&gt; season.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>my 2024 mtb racing season summary</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/fttseason2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/fttseason2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For me, mountain bike racing is not something I&amp;rsquo;m super into, so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t pay much to do it like I do &lt;a href=&#34;../cx/&#34;&gt;cyclocross&lt;/a&gt;, but the &lt;a href=&#34;../ftt/&#34;&gt;Fat Tire Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; races had always looked like fun so in 2024 I took the plunge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race 1&lt;/strong&gt; 2024-05-14: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/segments/37005832&#34;&gt;stravalink&lt;/a&gt; Started off with steep uphill on rocky surface. I got caught behind a couple of riders who went way slower than I could have, putting me in a hole the rest of the race. I was chasing a Hardcore Bike Club rider for most of the rest of the race. I gained time on the ups; he gained time everywhere else. There was one descent that was steep, kind of muddy and had a turn into a bridge right at the bottom. I had a tough time with it on my practice lap and managed to wipe out on it in Lap 2 (I&amp;rsquo;m a B-Group rider so I only did 3 laps).&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5/6 for 6 points&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race 2&lt;/strong&gt; 2024-05-28&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/segments/37005757&#34;&gt;stravalink&lt;/a&gt; There was a prologue to stretch the group out a little before hitting the singletrack this week. Loads of climbing on this course. I was following one rider for most of the first lap before a pedal strike knocked me to a halt and my lost momentum meant I didn&amp;rsquo;t see her again until the last third of the third lap. The rooty climb was tough, and I messed up the line on lap 2. In the end I was lapped by a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of the fast group riders (by two of them in lap 2).&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;9/10 for 2 points&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race 3&lt;/strong&gt; 2024-06-18&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/segments/37144430&#34;&gt;stravalink&lt;/a&gt; The organizers made this a shorter loop because the Oilers were playing a must-win game in the Stanley Cup Final, so they wanted us to get out of there quickly. I was chasing another B-group rider on the second lap who, when she passed me said &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry; I&amp;rsquo;m slow on the downhills.&amp;rdquo; So as she was opening more of a gap going down I tried to go faster and then a moment of inattention meant I clipped my bars on a tree and crashed. It hurt. I finished the race, but never did catch up with her.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4/6 for 7 points&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race 4&lt;/strong&gt; 2024-06-25: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/segments/37193026&#34;&gt;stravalink&lt;/a&gt; This was pretty much the same course as the first FTT race of the year (although for some reason, the segment says it&amp;rsquo;s longer). I wiped out on that same off-camber descent I had trouble with in May, but managed to hang onto 2nd place in the B-Group nonetheless. Climbing is definitely where I gain a bit of time in these races.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2/4 for 9 points&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race 5&lt;/strong&gt; 2024-07-02: Missed the race because of my kid&amp;rsquo;s soccer game. They had a Le Mans style start&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; though, which sounded fun.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race 6&lt;/strong&gt; 2024-07-09: Missed the race because I was in Valemount doing a little mountain biking. This was a team trivia race, and I have no idea how that works.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was no race on May 21 because the radar showed rain, but it never came. I got a ride in that night anyway, since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been able to check Strava in time.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>spring again</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240425-spring-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 13:26:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240425-spring-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is almost the end of April in 2024 and my Strava account says I&amp;rsquo;m in better shape than I was at any point last year. I&amp;rsquo;ve been out for a couple of &lt;a href=&#34;../vcc/&#34;&gt;VCC&lt;/a&gt; rides this season where it&amp;rsquo;s been about 11 degrees and I wore my tights and seemed to fit in pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the first week there was a fast group and a slow group, which I definitely knew I should stick with (Strava number notwithstanding). My suspicions were justified the next week when chatting with one of the riders who&amp;rsquo;d been in the first week fast group. Apparently their average speed wasn&amp;rsquo;t that crazy, but they&amp;rsquo;re so strong in the wind. Some of them used to be Cat 1&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; racers so yeah, best shape of my life is still going to leave me in a puddle by the side of the road keeping up with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>watching star trek</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240320-watching-startrek/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 10:40:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240320-watching-startrek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been years since Star Trek was really important to me. Decades. When I was a teen The Next Generation was (along with the Simpsons and the X-Files) the fiction I loved most. I loved the stories; I loved the vision of the future; most of all I loved the characters and could think of nothing better than flying around having adventures solving problems with a found family&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s still something I love the idea of, and pretty much is my mental model of what I wanted out of a working life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>watching cross</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240202-watching-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 12:12:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240202-watching-cross/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2022 I began actually watching cyclocross races. My kid still had &amp;ldquo;naps&amp;rdquo; on days when he wasn&amp;rsquo;t at school and I discovered that YouTube could show me what had been going on in Belgium that morning. It was &amp;lsquo;kerstperiode&amp;rsquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; so there were a pile of races to get thoroughly immersed in. I&amp;rsquo;d watch most of a race and then get the final lap queued up for when C could come out of his room and we would watch 15 minutes of muddy bike racing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>my 2023 season summary</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2023 I was hoping to be a better racer. I spent the winter actually using the gym we have at work, doing time on the stationary bike so as not to lose all my kilometres in my legs. They say you should do strength training and I tried but it&amp;rsquo;s a pain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The other thing I did was join a club. &lt;a href=&#34;https://velocitycyclingclub.ca&#34;&gt;Velocity Cycling Club&lt;/a&gt; is my new bunch. We have a coach and club jerseys and it&amp;rsquo;s all a bit more community-building than the lone-wolf cyclist thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing. I went on a couple of group rides and they were fun. The first was about 60km and easy riding. I self-selected to the slow group, and was the only person in it (along with the bunch leader). But it was good. I got to learn about some of the group riding norms and hand signals. Old Paul was very welcoming in general and did a good job showing me how to get close to people in the bunch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity cycling club</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/vcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/vcc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://velocitycyclingclub.ca&#34;&gt;Velocity Cycling Club&lt;/a&gt; is the group I ride with. There are a few clubs in the Edmonton area that I could have joined. I was going to join &lt;a href=&#34;https://ertc.org/&#34;&gt;ERTC (Edmonton Road and Track Club)&lt;/a&gt; back in 2020 but doing things in groups wasn&amp;rsquo;t feasible that year. I ended up with VCC mostly because a couple of the older guys from their club were friendly at a few of my &lt;a href=&#34;cxseason2022.md&#34;&gt;2022 cyclocross races&lt;/a&gt;. Also, nice jerseys without extraneous advertising.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>back on the bike</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240126-back-on-the-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 11:19:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240126-back-on-the-bike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m riding my bike again. It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months off dealing with some other issues, but I&amp;rsquo;m making my legs go &amp;lsquo;round in circles again. The big difference compared with last winter is that I&amp;rsquo;m riding indoors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got a Wahoo smart trainer in fall when the &lt;a href=&#34;../../tags/cx/&#34;&gt;cyclocross&lt;/a&gt; season was getting smoked out and it was dangerous to go outside and breathe heavily. It was heavily on sale because it isn&amp;rsquo;t a full-on smart trainer that replaces your rear wheel and has a computer out front built in. It&amp;rsquo;s the kind that rolls against your rear tire&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reintroduction</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240113-reintroduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:12:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240113-reintroduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hello-again&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  hello again&#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#hello-again&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m J Jack Unrau. I used to write on the internet some. I haven&amp;rsquo;t for several years. But the muscles should still work. I think.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plan here is to fill in some gaps. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe I&amp;rsquo;ll be getting as library-ish as &lt;a href=&#34;https://librarianaut.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;the old librarianaut blog&lt;/a&gt; ever was. There&amp;rsquo;ll be more about &lt;a href=&#34;../../tags/cycling/&#34;&gt;bikes&lt;/a&gt; than there ever used to be. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing too much about my kid, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scars</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/231017-scars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/231017-scars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my first cyclocross race I was riding around afterwards and hit a pothole in &lt;a href=&#34;../strathconasciencepark/&#34;&gt;Strathcona Science Park&lt;/a&gt; whacking my right ankle on my pedal and gouging a chunk out of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Training for my 2023 cx season I slipped my right foot and gouged my ankle on my big ring. This one probably could have used stitches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Half a week before entering the &lt;a href=&#34;../hopnhurl2023/&#34;&gt;Hop n Hurl race&lt;/a&gt; I was cruising downhill to &lt;a href=&#34;../capilanopark/&#34;&gt;Capilano Park&lt;/a&gt; for some good cx practice. The offroad downhill goes into Rundle park and is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trailforks.com/trails/get-ready-to-rundle-60390/&#34;&gt;get ready to rundle&lt;/a&gt; on TrailForks. I was descending on the hoods, not in the drops and I guess my weight wasn&amp;rsquo;t far enough back so when I hit the hard rut and my front wheel turned I went over the bars. I didn&amp;rsquo;t hit my head but got my knees, hip, wrist and ribs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>embrace the suck</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230919-embrace-the-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230919-embrace-the-suck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Embrace the suck&amp;rdquo;[^1]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href=&#34;../cx/&#34;&gt;cx&lt;/a&gt; rider this ethos means a lot. In cross you&amp;rsquo;re often racing in bad weather, cold weather, slippery weather. The courses are designed to make it hard for you to go quickly, not like a road bike race. All the twists and turns and lack of traction can make it so the fast people don&amp;rsquo;t get to use their speed, and craftiness, technique comes to the fore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>preparing for a season</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230829-prepping-a-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230829-prepping-a-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Alberta Bicycle Association Cyclo-cross Cup begins this weekend with the &lt;a href=&#34;../tubsontubs2023/&#34;&gt;Tubs on Tubs&lt;/a&gt; race and the &lt;a href=&#34;../velocitycross2023/&#34;&gt;Velocity CX&lt;/a&gt; and I am excited.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These races take place at &lt;a href=&#34;../strathconasciencepark&#34;&gt;Strathcona Science Park&lt;/a&gt;, which is a five minute ride from my house, so it&amp;rsquo;s my closest thing to a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; race and where I do most of my ripping around on grass to practice &amp;lsquo;crossing. The other day I was out there and saw someone else also riding around on the grass and flagged her down. Turned out she was one of the race organizers planning out the course.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;cross is coming (2023 edition)</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230824-cross-anticipation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230824-cross-anticipation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is August and &amp;lsquo;Cross is Coming&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m getting excited because cyclocross&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is for whatever reason my favourite kind of bike racing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I say &amp;ldquo;for whatever reason&amp;rdquo; because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem intuitive to me that this would be my favourite. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big powerful rider pushing massive watts. I fall over a lot riding around on rough terrain. I don&amp;rsquo;t like being cold and wet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But yet, when I did my first cyclocross race I enjoyed it. I came back &lt;a href=&#34;../cxseason2022/&#34;&gt;last year to do more&lt;/a&gt;. And even though I&amp;rsquo;m in the slowest category racing against kids and old guys, I really like it. I feel exhausted at the end of a race but I want to do it again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>go team optimism</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230530-coaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230530-coaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I joined &lt;a href=&#34;../vcc/&#34;&gt;a cycling club&lt;/a&gt; in 2023 and we have a coach. I have never had a coach before. I haven&amp;rsquo;t ever really done sports so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what a coach is supposed to do. But Kevin seems earnest and nice and is trying so hard to be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before this season&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../stiedaclassic2023/&#34;&gt;first race&lt;/a&gt; he held a racers&amp;rsquo; meeting to go over the course using veloviewer and to talk about tactics and what we should be doing before a race. I was at work that night, so I asked if he&amp;rsquo;d be able to record it and he did. He talked about wind directions and planning and prep and where to attack the group if we had the legs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bike racing season 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rode cyclocross races in 2022 but they didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like cyclocross. They aren&amp;rsquo;t muddy and cold&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Part of that was due to the boiling frog that we are as a planet but part of that is due to living in Edmonton, where we don&amp;rsquo;t really get shoulder seasons. The abrupt floompf of winter that happened on November 2 starts fatbike season, not a time for racing in mud, like in Europe (or even Victoria, which is where the Canadian nationals are going to be happening in November).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>aggression</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/190101-aggression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 11:14:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/190101-aggression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-agression&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  on agression&#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#on-agression&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#39;book-hint &#39;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Images which idealize (like most fashion and animal photography) are no less aggressive than work which makes a virtue of plainness (like class pictures, still lifes of the bleaker sort, and mug shots). There is an aggression implicit in every use of the camera.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Photography&lt;/em&gt; - Susan Sontag&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I take pictures of my kid every day almost. He&amp;rsquo;s young; this kind of behaviour is expected. I do it now because when he ages into being able to give consent he might not want me to. Will he see this as aggression? I do my best to not be controlling in how I steal pictures from people (inanimate objects are different, but not landscapes I realize), but will he resist my aggression, gentle as I try to make it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>edmonton and legends of exile</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/180824-feanor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 15:37:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/180824-feanor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The smoke from wildfires has been darkening our skies in Edmonton, and I realized when biking between the flames of the Suncor refineries that the grim brown greyness, the miasma of grit, this is what it feels like to live in Edmonton compared to Nanaimo. It isn&amp;rsquo;t always so externalized but even on the days when the sky is clear this is a foul place to be exiled.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m reading &lt;em&gt;The Silmarillion&lt;/em&gt; these days and I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize how much I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s elves. I&amp;rsquo;m hurt by and see my own follies in Feanor&amp;rsquo;s foolish oaths that lead to exile and ruin. That it&amp;rsquo;s told in high-spoken language makes it feel more significant than my bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>heading east for sunsets and seasons</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/161028-eastward/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 02:20:36 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/161028-eastward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In followup to the last post, yes, I did enjoy Nanaimo more than Campbell River. But now it&amp;rsquo;s time to be moving again. My partner and I are headed to Edmonton to start new jobs on November 7th. It&amp;rsquo;s a return to the prairies for me and I think I&amp;rsquo;ll like it better than I did when last I lived in Winnipeg.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my 30s out on the west coast and I do like the mildness of the winters here. But maybe it&amp;rsquo;s okay to live somewhere a little harder to deal with. A little (lot) colder, but with better food (non-sushi division). The new job should be much better than working for my former employer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>winning awards</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/150601-winning-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 17:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/150601-winning-awards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around our workplace there&amp;rsquo;s a joke that we should all be putting &amp;ldquo;award-winning librarian&amp;rdquo; in our bios when we show up in the outside world. After all, who is to say that the participation award from your grade 4 track meet isn&amp;rsquo;t what made you the professional you are today?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve totally done it though. I called myself award-winning in the bio for a talk Jason and I gave at the Vancouver Island Library Staff Conference a few weeks ago, because I really did win an award for making radio back in journalism school. It seemed relevant as part of my radio librarian bona fides. But whatever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mobility</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/140831-mobility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 05:36:49 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/140831-mobility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I finish my month-long move down to Nanaimo for &lt;a href=&#34;http://librarianaut.wordpress.com/2014/08/25/not-quite-a-comeback/&#34;&gt;my new job&lt;/a&gt;. By this time next week though, I&amp;rsquo;ll be on vacation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope I like Nanaimo better than Campbell River. I feel kind of bad for not liking it here. There are some very nice people in this town, but nothing ever really clicked for me. I will miss the folks from Coho Books.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Nanaimo there are comic and game shops I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to bike to. The ferry to Vancouver is way closer and easier. I know a bunch of people there already (yes, most of them are librarians) so maybe I won&amp;rsquo;t have to live on the internet quite so much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>your friendly neighbourhood wretched hive of scum &amp; villainy - a presentation</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/120920-your-friendly-neighbourhood-wretched-hive-of-scum-villainy-a-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 04:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/120920-your-friendly-neighbourhood-wretched-hive-of-scum-villainy-a-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#39;book-hint &#39;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;This is a slightly modified version of the text (and slides) from my talk at Oh, the Places You&amp;rsquo;ll Know, a part of SFU&amp;rsquo;s Public Square on September 19, 2012. We were encouraged to put practical considerations aside, hence the &amp;ldquo;damn the lawyers; full speed ahead!&amp;rdquo; approach advocated within.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;My big idea for public libraries is that they should embrace the role of &amp;ldquo;Your Friendly Neighbourhood Wretched Hive of Scum and Villainy.&amp;rdquo; To begin, and to situate us here, I agree with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newlibrarianship.org/&#34; title=&#34;The Atlas of New Librarianship&#34;&gt;R. David Lankes&lt;/a&gt; when he says &amp;ldquo;the mission of librarians is to facilitate knowledge creation in their communities.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s a great mission, but I think it is very easy for us to mis-define our communities. I want my library (and this is a hypothetical library - I&amp;rsquo;m not representing anyone&amp;rsquo;s views but my own here) to serve the community it&amp;rsquo;s in and not the rules of publishers, movie studios or lawmakers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
