<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 11:19:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>back on the bike</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/backonthebike/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 11:19:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/backonthebike/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m riding my bike again. It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months off dealing with some other issues, but I&amp;rsquo;m making my legs go &amp;lsquo;round in circles again. The big difference compared with last winter is that I&amp;rsquo;m riding indoors.&#xA;I got a Wahoo smart trainer in fall when the cyclocross season was getting smoked out and it was dangerous to go outside and breathe heavily. It was heavily on sale because it isn&amp;rsquo;t a full-on smart trainer that replaces your rear wheel and has a computer out front built in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reintroduction</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/reintroduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:12:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/reintroduction/</guid>
      <description>hello again I&amp;rsquo;m J Jack Unrau. I used to write on the internet some. I haven&amp;rsquo;t for several years. But the muscles should still work. I think.&#xA;The plan here is to fill in some gaps. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe I&amp;rsquo;ll be getting as library-ish as the old librarianaut blog ever was. There&amp;rsquo;ll be more about bikes than there ever used to be. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing too much about my kid, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity cross 2023 - smoked out</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Strathcona Science Park Course: stravalink (shared with Tubs on Tubs)&#xA;Sidney McGill was going to be racing in the Open Men category and I was really excited to see her, and to race in the Novice Men, but by 7am the AQHI was over 10 and no one wanted to get blacklung for a race (also the Alberta Bicycle Association won&amp;rsquo;t let you do anything if the index is over 7).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs supercalifragilisticexpialidocius prestige</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Strathcona Science Park Course: stravalink&#xA;Tubs on Tubs Supercalifragilisticexpialidocius Prestige was the race that was going to open up the 2023 ABA [[CX]] season. And it did for the Novice Men, Sport Men and Sport Women categories, but sadly, the AQHI hit 11 and the afternoon races had to be cancelled (along with the next day&amp;rsquo;s entire Velocity CX Race).&#xA;But I got my race in, and it was really fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>aggression</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/aggression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 11:14:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/aggression/</guid>
      <description>on agression Images which idealize (like most fashion and animal photography) are no less aggressive than work which makes a virtue of plainness (like class pictures, still lifes of the bleaker sort, and mug shots). There is an aggression implicit in every use of the camera.&#xA;On Photography - Susan Sontag&#xA;I take pictures of my kid every day almost. He&amp;rsquo;s young; this kind of behaviour is expected. I do it now because when he ages into being able to give consent he might not want me to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>edmonton and legends of exile</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/feanor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 15:37:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/feanor/</guid>
      <description>The smoke from wildfires has been darkening our skies in Edmonton, and I realized when biking between the flames of the Suncor refineries that the grim brown greyness, the miasma of grit, this is what it feels like to live in Edmonton compared to Nanaimo. It isn&amp;rsquo;t always so externalized but even on the days when the sky is clear this is a foul place to be exiled.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m reading The Silmarillion these days and I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize how much I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s elves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>heading east for sunsets and seasons</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/eastward/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 02:20:36 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/eastward/</guid>
      <description>In followup to the last post, yes, I did enjoy Nanaimo more than Campbell River. But now it&amp;rsquo;s time to be moving again. My partner and I are headed to Edmonton to start new jobs on November 7th. It&amp;rsquo;s a return to the prairies for me and I think I&amp;rsquo;ll like it better than I did when last I lived in Winnipeg.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my 30s out on the west coast and I do like the mildness of the winters here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mobility</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/mobility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 05:36:49 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/mobility/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow I finish my month-long move down to Nanaimo for my new job. By this time next week though, I&amp;rsquo;ll be on vacation.&#xA;I hope I like Nanaimo better than Campbell River. I feel kind of bad for not liking it here. There are some very nice people in this town, but nothing ever really clicked for me. I will miss the folks from Coho Books.&#xA;In Nanaimo there are comic and game shops I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to bike to.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
