<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thedubiousmonk on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thedubiousmonk on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>cyclocross</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/essays/cx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/essays/cx/</guid>
      <description>Cyclocross (also cyclo-cross, &amp;lsquo;cross or cx) is my favourite discipline of riding bikes. There are a bunch of reasons for that, which I&amp;rsquo;ll be detailing below, along with some history and further reading1 by people who know more than me.&#xA;cyclocross as a sport So you know about riding a bike right? Bikes have two wheels and pedals and handlebars to steer. The important thing you learn as a kid is how to balance and then off you go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cyclocross</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cx/</guid>
      <description>Cyclocross (also cyclo-cross, &amp;lsquo;cross or cx) is my favourite discipline of riding bikes. In its contemporary form you ride your bike around in a field and sometimes have to get off your bike and carry it because the hills are too steep or there are stairs or someone put a bunch of boards across the track. I often think of it as the least efficient way of using your bike. It&amp;rsquo;s awesome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>watching star trek</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240320-watching-startrek/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 10:40:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240320-watching-startrek/</guid>
      <description>It has been years since Star Trek was really important to me. Decades. When I was a teen The Next Generation was (along with the Simpsons and the X-Files) the fiction I loved most. I loved the stories; I loved the vision of the future; most of all I loved the characters and could think of nothing better than flying around having adventures solving problems with a found family1. That&amp;rsquo;s still something I love the idea of, and pretty much is my mental model of what I wanted out of a working life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>watching cross</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240202-watching-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 12:12:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240202-watching-cross/</guid>
      <description>At the end of 2022 I began actually watching cyclocross races. My kid still had &amp;ldquo;naps&amp;rdquo; on days when he wasn&amp;rsquo;t at school and I discovered that YouTube could show me what had been going on in Belgium that morning. It was &amp;lsquo;kerstperiode&amp;rsquo;1 so there were a pile of races to get thoroughly immersed in. I&amp;rsquo;d watch most of a race and then get the final lap queued up for when C could come out of his room and we would watch 15 minutes of muddy bike racing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>my 2023 season summary</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2023/</guid>
      <description>In 2023 I was hoping to be a better racer. I spent the winter actually using the gym we have at work, doing time on the stationary bike so as not to lose all my kilometres in my legs. They say you should do strength training and I tried but it&amp;rsquo;s a pain.&#xA;The other thing I did was join a club. Velocity Cycling Club is my new bunch. We have a coach and club jerseys and it&amp;rsquo;s all a bit more community-building than the lone-wolf cyclist thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity cycling club</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/vcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/vcc/</guid>
      <description>Velocity Cycling Club is the group I ride with. There are a few clubs in the Edmonton area that I could have joined. I was going to join ERTC (Edmonton Road and Track Club) back in 2020 but doing things in groups wasn&amp;rsquo;t feasible that year. I ended up with VCC mostly because a couple of the older guys from their club were friendly at a few of my 2022 cyclocross races.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>back on the bike</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240126-back-on-the-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 11:19:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240126-back-on-the-bike/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m riding my bike again. It&amp;rsquo;s been a few months off dealing with some other issues, but I&amp;rsquo;m making my legs go &amp;lsquo;round in circles again. The big difference compared with last winter is that I&amp;rsquo;m riding indoors.&#xA;I got a Wahoo smart trainer in fall when the cyclocross season was getting smoked out and it was dangerous to go outside and breathe heavily. It was heavily on sale because it isn&amp;rsquo;t a full-on smart trainer that replaces your rear wheel and has a computer out front built in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 10:51:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/about/</guid>
      <description>I am not a monk. I have not withdrawn to natural remoteness. No swamps or rocky islands surround me, just refineries and politics I despise. I work in a digital world. Silicon and glass and user interfaces are the obstacles I help people navigate at work. I tend to use those tools well so I serve by putting those skills to work for the public.&#xA;But.&#xA;More and more I hate am disenchanted with this world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reintroduction</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240113-reintroduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 12:12:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240113-reintroduction/</guid>
      <description>hello again I&amp;rsquo;m J Jack Unrau. I used to write on the internet some. I haven&amp;rsquo;t for several years. But the muscles should still work. I think.&#xA;The plan here is to fill in some gaps. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe I&amp;rsquo;ll be getting as library-ish as the old librarianaut blog ever was. There&amp;rsquo;ll be more about bikes than there ever used to be. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing too much about my kid, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>crossbow semiprestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/crossbow2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/crossbow2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Rutland Park, Calgary Course: stravalink I missed out on writing this up at the end of the 2023 CX season, and now that 2024 has come around, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a bunch of the data I like to put in these race writeups. Nonetheless, here&amp;rsquo;s what I can find (thankfully I did do my CrossResults upload back when the race happened).&#xA;This race was postponed from earlier in the month because of some freakish weather.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>snakes &amp; ladders III 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/snakesladders2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/snakesladders2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Snakes Head Natural Area, Sundre Course: stravalink I missed out on writing this up at the end of the 2023 CX season, and now that 2024 has come around, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a bunch of the data I like to put in these race writeups. Nonetheless, here&amp;rsquo;s what I can find (thankfully I did do my CrossResults upload back when the race happened).&#xA;results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Adam ROBERTS Brendan CARDIFF1 Jason PROCHE Novice Men Cor SINKE William KINDZIERSKI Arun WARD Open Men Mark FAGNAN Andrew DAVIDSON Scott DESMARAIS Open Women Francesca SEAL Susanne MCARTHUR Quinn FLATER Sport Men Josh BARKER Sean SWEENEY Carl MILLER Sport Women Kathryn SWEENEY Hazel ROBERTS Madeline MAGLEO my results did not race read more Velocity Cycling Club woo!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scars</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/231017-scars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/231017-scars/</guid>
      <description>In my first cyclocross race I was riding around afterwards and hit a pothole in Strathcona Science Park whacking my right ankle on my pedal and gouging a chunk out of it.&#xA;Training for my 2023 cx season I slipped my right foot and gouged my ankle on my big ring. This one probably could have used stitches.&#xA;Half a week before entering the Hop n Hurl race I was cruising downhill to Capilano Park for some good cx practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>baby walter cross 2023 - day 2</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-2/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Queen Elizabeth Park Edmonton Course: stravalink I had hoped to do more racing this year, but it turned out that four was what I could handle with my work and other life commitments. So the second day of Baby Walter Cross was my season closer.&#xA;1&#xA;The course this year went the opposite direction of 2022 which I think I preferred. The climbing of the stupid hill was still tough, but the descents weren&amp;rsquo;t terrifying and we got to skip the runup in favour of a singletrack descent (with roots that were highlighted but you needed to dodge).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>baby walter cross 2023 - day 1</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-1/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Queen Elizabeth Park Edmonton Course: stravalink Baby Walter Cross is a two-day race put on by the Alberta Cyclocross Collective, which isn&amp;rsquo;t a club exactly, just all the cx lovers in Edmonton. The park has a really big hill, which makes for a lot of climbing.&#xA;Apparently on the Saturday race (which I didn&amp;rsquo;t attend) there were some big crashes by people trying to bunny-hop the obstacles and failing badly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>terrascape beans n barley 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/bicicross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/bicicross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Richmond Green Park, Calgary Course: stravalink I missed out on writing this up at the end of the 2023 CX season, and now that 2024 has come around, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a bunch of the data I like to put in these race writeups. Nonetheless, here&amp;rsquo;s what I can find (thankfully I did do my CrossResults upload back when the race happened).&#xA;results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Larix HALLETT Emile VOGEL-NAKAMURA Spencer POOTZ Novice Men Cor SINKE William LEMIEUX Emmet MACKLEM Open Men Eric BERG Ryan MACLEAN Mark FAGNAN Open Women Jenaya FRANCIS Nico KNOLL Francesca SEAL Sport Men Joel DYCK Sean SWEENEY Brendan CARDIFF1 Sport Women Tayte PROULX-ROYDS Hazel ROBERTS Kathryn SWEENEY my results did not race read more Velocity Cycling Club woo!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bicicross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/bicicross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/bicicross2023/</guid>
      <description> Tech Guide Location: Richmond Green Park, Calgary Course: stravalink I missed out on writing this up at the end of the 2023 CX season, and now that 2024 has come around, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a bunch of the data I like to put in these race writeups. Nonetheless, here&amp;rsquo;s what I can find (thankfully I did do my CrossResults upload back when the race happened).&#xA;results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Emile VOGEL-NAKAMURA Larix HALLETT Spencer POOTZ Novice Men William LEMIEUX Carson BROWN Douglas GRAY Open Men Eric BERG Andrew DAVIDSON Mark FAGNAN Open Women Jenaya FRANCIS Nico KNOLL Kelsey DUFFIELD Sport Men Joel DYCK Clarke ELLIS Sean SWEENEY Sport Women Tayte PROULX-ROYDS Kathryn SWEENEY Hazel ROBERTS my results did not race read more </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hardcore hop n hurl 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/hopnhurl2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/hopnhurl2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Voyageur Park Devon Course: stravalink I came into this race knowing that last year&amp;rsquo;s Puncheur Cross was my favourite. Unfortunately I had a training crash the Tuesday before this race, which put me in kind of a bad place. Mostly scraped up, but also a bit of a bruised wrist and some bruised ribs. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d be okay to race still, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t setting my expectations too high.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>drie zussen superprestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</guid>
      <description> Tech Guide Location: Canmore Nordic Centre Canmore Course: stravalink ABA Cup race. Construction on the course. Looked beautiful in the mountains. This is where I&amp;rsquo;d like to go for a travelling race next year.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Open Women Christiane BILODEAU Nico KNOLL Kelsey DUFFIELD Open Men Mark FAGNAN Finn BORSTMAYER Eric BERG Expert Men Jacob PLAYFAIR Larix HALLETT Brett GREINER Novice Men Petr HOLUB Mitchell ROBERTS Emmett MACKLEM Sport Men Patrick MCCRADY Nigel BAINES Sean SWEENEY Sport Women Lydia STACK-MICHASIW Daena SIDNEY Kathryn SWEENEY my results Did not race read more bike stuff </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>puncheur cross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/puncheurcross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/puncheurcross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Voyageur Park Devon Course: stravalink This was Provincials for this year, which seems early.&#xA;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t at this race, but Nancy St-Hilaire has good pictures on her SmugMug.&#xA;results Official Results CrossResults Podia Open Women Jenaya FRANCIS Nico KNOLL Christiane BILODEAU Open Men Eric BERG Ryan MACLEAN 1 Andrew DAVIDSON Junior Women Dakota DIXON U17 Women Madeline MAGLEO Lily GORDON U15 Women Hazel ROBERTS Sarah WELSH Eliza MCRAE Junior Men Graham FRANCIS Colton ZABOLOTNEY Ben MORIN U17 Men Larix HALLET Quinten MACKLEM Liam BATE U15 Men William KINDZIERSKI Finlay ROBERTS Riley OOSTERHOF Master Women 35-44 Bridget LINDER Jenn PROCHE Kristin BAKER Master Women 45+ Jay SMITH Michelle JACKMAN Daena SIDNEY Master Men 35-44 Graham DIEHL Blaine SHERMAN Adam ROBERTS Master Men 45-54 Paul MARTIN Randy PERRY David ROBERTS Master Men 55-64 Ed GARVIN Robert MARTENS Peter LAWRENCE Master Men 65+ Ken GERMAINE Gregory PATYCHUK Louis BUGEAUD Sport Women Alina CUSTODIO Leanne ERIKSON Alyssa BARKER Novice Men Emmett MACKLEM Jett FENTON Arun WARD my results Did not race read more My 2022 Experience at Puncheur Cross Only a 14 second gap between first and second for Provincial champion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>western cyclocross challenge 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</guid>
      <description> Tech Guide Location: Canmore Nordic Centre Canmore Course: stravalink Western Challenge CX. This race is done in age groups to get points for call-ups for Nationals and what have you.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Elite/Open Women Ella MYERS Christiane BILODEAU Francesca SEAL Junior Women Nico KNOLL Maria MCCARTNEY Keely HAMILTON U15 Women Hazel ROBERTS Eliza MCRAE U17 Women Lydia STACK-MICHASIW Brooke BATES Ella EIDSVIK Elite/Open Men Eric BERG Ryan MACLEAN Manu MOORE U15 Men James CHALKLEY William KINDZIERSKI Finlay ROBERTS U17 Men Ethan WOOD Larix HALLETT Quinten MACKLEM Masters Men 35-44 Andrew DAVIDSON Graham DIEHL Jesse BAUER Masters Men 45-54 Mark KNOLL Paul MARTIN David ROBERTS Masters Men 55-64 Ed GARVIN Peter LAWRENCE Robert MARTENS Masters Men 65+ Gregory PATYCHUK Ken GERMAINE John ATTO Masters Women 35-44 Pepper HARLTON Bridget LINDER Jenn PROCHE Masters Women 45-54 Susanne MCARTHUR Shantel KOENIG Shawna DONALDSON Masters Women 55-64 Rachel DUMONT Junior Men Ben MORIN Colton ZABOLOTNEY Rhett BATES my results Did not race read more </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>embrace the suck</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230919-embrace-the-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230919-embrace-the-suck/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Embrace the suck&amp;rdquo;[^1]&#xA;As a cx rider this ethos means a lot. In cross you&amp;rsquo;re often racing in bad weather, cold weather, slippery weather. The courses are designed to make it hard for you to go quickly, not like a road bike race. All the twists and turns and lack of traction can make it so the fast people don&amp;rsquo;t get to use their speed, and craftiness, technique comes to the fore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>school of cross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink Like the previous day&amp;rsquo;s Jim Horner Grand Prix ERTC&amp;rsquo;s School of Cross (p/b Blindman Brewing) 2023 race happened in Capilano Park. The air quality was a bit better on the day so only one race was cancelled (Open Women).&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Elite/Open Men Mark FAGNAN Graham FRANCIS Ryan MCLEAN Expert Men Paulo ALVES 1 Jacob PLAYFAIR Randy PERRY Novice Men Quinten MACKLEM2 Emmett MACKLEM Evan KINDZIERSKI Sport Men Ethan MCGHAN Ryan ARYCHUK Colin WEIR CHABA Sport Women Rachel DUMONT [^3] Kristin BAKER Madeline MAGLEO my results Did not race read more Earned promotion up to Open Men, with his second win (in a row, following JHGP) in Expert.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jim horner grand prix 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink I was so happy this race wasn&amp;rsquo;t taking place in Argyll Park this year. I hated the downhill that someone broke a collarbone on last year and lost so much time on it. Capilano Park was near my house and I could practice on it. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t practice hard enough on wet enough grass, because hoo boy did I not do well on that terrain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>capilano park</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/capilanopark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/capilanopark/</guid>
      <description>Capilano Park is a park in the city of Edmonton, where I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t actually expect a cx race to work, but it does.&#xA;As far as the singletrack in the park goes, this is where you connect up with Goldbar Park and the cool trails in there. I generally prefer riding Eastbound.&#xA;races Jim Horner Grand Prix 2023 School of Cross 2023 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the real diehl cyclocross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/peloton2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/peloton2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Canadian Southern Baptist Seminary - Cochrane Course: stravalink &amp;ldquo;The Real Diehl&amp;rdquo; Cyclocross&#xA;Peloton&amp;rsquo;s first CX race they&amp;rsquo;ve put on. Swag included a UCI tire checker.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Scott DESMARAIS Spencer POOTZ Larix HALLETT1 Novice Men Joel DYCK William LEMIEUX Douglas GRAY Open Men Andrew DAVIDSON Shawn BUNNIN Mark KNOLL Open Women Pepper HARLTON Kelsey DUFFIELD Nico KNOLL Sport Men Nigel BAINES Robert MARTENS Garth STOTTS Sport Women Alina CUSTODIO Hazel ROBERTS Elané FERGUSON my results Did not race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>deadgoat supercross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/deadgoat2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/deadgoat2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Canadian Southern Baptist Seminary - Cochrane Course: stravalink1 It looks like this was a hot and windy race.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Scott DESMARAIS Emile VOGEL-NAKAMURA Spencer POOTZ Novice Men Joel DYCK Karol SIARKA Quinten MACKLEM Open Men Andrew DAVIDSON Shawn BUNNIN Mark KNOLL Open Women Sidney MCGILL Ella MYERS Nico KNOLL Sport Men Larix HALLETT Patrick MCCRADY Nigel BAINES Sport Women Avree COLLING Hazel ROBERTS Hilary BUCKLEY my results Did not race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity cross 2023 - smoked out</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Strathcona Science Park Course: stravalink (shared with Tubs on Tubs) Sidney McGill was going to be racing in the Open Men category and I was really excited to see her, and to race in the Novice Men, but by 7am the AQHI was over 10 and no one wanted to get blacklung for a race (also the Alberta Bicycle Association won&amp;rsquo;t let you do anything if the index is over 7).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs supercalifragilisticexpialidocius prestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Strathcona Science Park Course: stravalink Tubs on Tubs Supercalifragilisticexpialidocius Prestige was the race that was going to open up the 2023 ABA CX season. And it did for the Novice Men, Sport Men and Sport Women categories, but sadly, the AQHI hit 11 and the afternoon races had to be cancelled (along with the next day&amp;rsquo;s entire Velocity CX Race).&#xA;But I got my race in, and it was really fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>midweek racing</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wnw2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wnw2023/</guid>
      <description>As part of my season preparations I decided to at least try the midweek cx racing that goes on in Edmonton. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird because it&amp;rsquo;s so casual and hard to find information about. There are people asking questions in the Alberta CX Facebook group and you get a response with a screenshot from somewhere(?) giving a schedule. It seems that the people who know, know.&#xA;And holy crap did a lot of people know about it last night!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>preparing for a season</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230829-prepping-a-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230829-prepping-a-season/</guid>
      <description>The Alberta Bicycle Association Cyclo-cross Cup begins this weekend with the Tubs on Tubs race and the Velocity CX and I am excited.&#xA;These races take place at Strathcona Science Park, which is a five minute ride from my house, so it&amp;rsquo;s my closest thing to a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; race and where I do most of my ripping around on grass to practice &amp;lsquo;crossing. The other day I was out there and saw someone else also riding around on the grass and flagged her down.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;cross is coming (2023 edition)</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230824-cross-anticipation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230824-cross-anticipation/</guid>
      <description>It is August and &amp;lsquo;Cross is Coming1. I&amp;rsquo;m getting excited because cyclocross2 is for whatever reason my favourite kind of bike racing.&#xA;I say &amp;ldquo;for whatever reason&amp;rdquo; because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem intuitive to me that this would be my favourite. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big powerful rider pushing massive watts. I fall over a lot riding around on rough terrain. I don&amp;rsquo;t like being cold and wet.&#xA;But yet, when I did my first cyclocross race I enjoyed it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity criterium 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycrit2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycrit2023/</guid>
      <description>Our club put on a criterium and in my effort to try out a few different kinds of racing (despite being a slowpoke) I entered. I rode in the Citizen class again because that&amp;rsquo;s the type of license I got for the season. This time there were three riders instead of two at the Stieda race earlier. The other guys (despite being in Citizen where all genders can enter, we were all dudes) had raced the day before with the iGregari SugarBoddy Criterium, which was on the same course but in the opposite direction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>go team optimism</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230530-coaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230530-coaching/</guid>
      <description>I joined a cycling club in 2023 and we have a coach. I have never had a coach before. I haven&amp;rsquo;t ever really done sports (part of why my partner tells me I&amp;rsquo;m not an athlete) so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what a coach is supposed to do. But Kevin seems earnest and nice and is trying so hard to be helpful.&#xA;Before this season&amp;rsquo;s first race he held a racers&amp;rsquo; meeting to go over the course using veloviewer and to talk about tactics and what we should be doing before a race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>stieda classic 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2023/</guid>
      <description>We only had two people in my category for this race. The category being Citizen, which is supposed to be a mixed gender, less intense beginner kind of racing. The other guy, Keith, was also part of my cycling club but he said he was only in this class by mistake. He was confused and could probably have been in the Mens&amp;rsquo; Category 4. But there we were.&#xA;We got to start with the Women Cat 4 group which was awesome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bike racing season 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2022/</guid>
      <description>I rode cyclocross races in 2022 but they didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like cyclocross. They aren&amp;rsquo;t muddy and cold1. Part of that was due to the boiling frog that we are as a planet but part of that is due to living in Edmonton, where we don&amp;rsquo;t really get shoulder seasons. The abrupt floompf of winter that happened on November 2 starts fatbike season, not a time for racing in mud, like in Europe (or even Victoria, which is where the Canadian nationals are going to be happening in November).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>zombie baby walter cross 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2022/</guid>
      <description>I was the last competitor across the line in the Novice class of the Zombie Baby Walter Cross race. But a bunch of people had been lapped or did not finish, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually in last place. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how that feels.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not so funny how it feels to wipe out trying to turn while sliding down a grassy hill. Which I did. But I kept going, gritting my teeth while kids in my race were bunny-hopping the barriers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>puncheur cross 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/puncheurcross2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/puncheurcross2022/</guid>
      <description>I loved the Devon Puncheur race. I also love that it got a writeup entitled The Best Grassroots Cyclocross Race You&amp;rsquo;ve Never Heard of1 I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been to Devon, which is just southwest of Edmonton, before this race, but Voyageur Park was a really nice example of this region&amp;rsquo;s river valley terrain. The course went through the trees, around a flat corkscrew feature, down by the river and was my introduction to sand on a &amp;lsquo;cross course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jim horner grand prix 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2022/</guid>
      <description>My second race of the 2022 cyclocross season was presented by the Juventus Cycling Club at the Argyll Velodrome. Not in the velodrome itself, but the park surrounding it. When I was looking at the map in the preceding days I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure where the ups and downs and how it would work as a course. There was a toboggan hill. Were we going to have to up that? Down it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs superduper prestige 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2022/</guid>
      <description>I returned to cyclocross in 2022, and went back to the same race in the same park. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that makes this a classic or not.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d tested this course beforehand. My house is just across the river from the &amp;ldquo;indestructible Strathcona Science Park&amp;rdquo;1 so this was where I&amp;rsquo;d been riding up and down hills and practicing my off-cambers the week before.&#xA;2&#xA;In the tech guide the organizers had released it looked like the really super-steep downhill I&amp;rsquo;d wiped out on in my practice laps back in 2019 was not part of the course, which I appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>strathcona science park</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/strathconasciencepark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/strathconasciencepark/</guid>
      <description>Strathcona Science Park is a provincial park just outside Edmonton. It&amp;rsquo;s rutted and full of gopher holes and apparently has toxic seepage in places. There&amp;rsquo;s no sandy area but it does have a big downhill with long stairs for a runup.&#xA;This is my &amp;ldquo;home course&amp;rdquo; because I used to live just across the river, so it&amp;rsquo;s a convenient place to practice my cx race techniques, do laps to build my stamina and just generally rip around.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>stieda classic 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/stiedaclassic2022/</guid>
      <description>My knee went pop in the last 7km of the ride and Mike who I&amp;rsquo;d been riding with left me behind. It was all right though. I was going to finish my first road race. And yes, I was slow, but that was okay.&#xA;results 43rd place (out of 50 in Category 5)&#xA;Average Speed 27.72 km/h&#xA;2:03:22 (2 Laps) 33:59 behind winner&#xA;Lap 1 49:32 Lap 2 1:13:49 (note that this lap was longer) Zone 4 Results</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>aggression</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/190101-aggression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 11:14:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/190101-aggression/</guid>
      <description>on agression Images which idealize (like most fashion and animal photography) are no less aggressive than work which makes a virtue of plainness (like class pictures, still lifes of the bleaker sort, and mug shots). There is an aggression implicit in every use of the camera.&#xA;On Photography - Susan Sontag&#xA;I take pictures of my kid every day almost. He&amp;rsquo;s young; this kind of behaviour is expected. I do it now because when he ages into being able to give consent he might not want me to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>edmonton and legends of exile</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/180824-feanor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 15:37:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/180824-feanor/</guid>
      <description>The smoke from wildfires has been darkening our skies in Edmonton, and I realized when biking between the flames of the Suncor refineries that the grim brown greyness, the miasma of grit, this is what it feels like to live in Edmonton compared to Nanaimo. It isn&amp;rsquo;t always so externalized but even on the days when the sky is clear this is a foul place to be exiled.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m reading The Silmarillion these days and I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize how much I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s elves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>heading east for sunsets and seasons</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/161028-eastward/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 02:20:36 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/161028-eastward/</guid>
      <description>In followup to the last post, yes, I did enjoy Nanaimo more than Campbell River. But now it&amp;rsquo;s time to be moving again. My partner and I are headed to Edmonton to start new jobs on November 7th. It&amp;rsquo;s a return to the prairies for me and I think I&amp;rsquo;ll like it better than I did when last I lived in Winnipeg.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my 30s out on the west coast and I do like the mildness of the winters here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>winning awards</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/150601-winning-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 17:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/150601-winning-awards/</guid>
      <description>Around our workplace there&amp;rsquo;s a joke that we should all be putting &amp;ldquo;award-winning librarian&amp;rdquo; in our bios when we show up in the outside world. After all, who is to say that the participation award from your grade 4 track meet isn&amp;rsquo;t what made you the professional you are today?&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve totally done it though. I called myself award-winning in the bio for a talk Jason and I gave at the Vancouver Island Library Staff Conference a few weeks ago, because I really did win an award for making radio back in journalism school.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mobility</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/140831-mobility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 05:36:49 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/140831-mobility/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow I finish my month-long move down to Nanaimo for my new job. By this time next week though, I&amp;rsquo;ll be on vacation.&#xA;I hope I like Nanaimo better than Campbell River. I feel kind of bad for not liking it here. There are some very nice people in this town, but nothing ever really clicked for me. I will miss the folks from Coho Books.&#xA;In Nanaimo there are comic and game shops I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to bike to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>your friendly neighbourhood wretched hive of scum &amp; villainy - a presentation</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/120920-your-friendly-neighbourhood-wretched-hive-of-scum-villainy-a-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 04:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/120920-your-friendly-neighbourhood-wretched-hive-of-scum-villainy-a-presentation/</guid>
      <description>This is a slightly modified version of the text (and slides) from my talk at Oh, the Places You&amp;rsquo;ll Know, a part of SFU&amp;rsquo;s Public Square on September 19, 2012. We were encouraged to put practical considerations aside, hence the &amp;ldquo;damn the lawyers; full speed ahead!&amp;rdquo; approach advocated within.&#xA;My big idea for public libraries is that they should embrace the role of &amp;ldquo;Your Friendly Neighbourhood Wretched Hive of Scum and Villainy.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
