<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rmcc on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/rmcc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rmcc on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/rmcc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>drie zussen superprestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</guid>
      <description> Tech Guide Location: Canmore Nordic Centre Canmore Course: stravalink ABA Cup race. Construction on the course. Looked beautiful in the mountains. This is where I&amp;rsquo;d like to go for a travelling race next year.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Open Women Christiane BILODEAU Nico KNOLL Kelsey DUFFIELD Open Men Mark FAGNAN Finn BORSTMAYER Eric BERG Expert Men Jacob PLAYFAIR Larix HALLETT Brett GREINER Novice Men Petr HOLUB Mitchell ROBERTS Emmett MACKLEM Sport Men Patrick MCCRADY Nigel BAINES Sean SWEENEY Sport Women Lydia STACK-MICHASIW Daena SIDNEY Kathryn SWEENEY my results Did not race read more bike stuff </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>western cyclocross challenge 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</guid>
      <description> Tech Guide Location: Canmore Nordic Centre Canmore Course: stravalink Western Challenge CX. This race is done in age groups to get points for call-ups for Nationals and what have you.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Elite/Open Women Ella MYERS Christiane BILODEAU Francesca SEAL Junior Women Nico KNOLL Maria MCCARTNEY Keely HAMILTON U15 Women Hazel ROBERTS Eliza MCRAE U17 Women Lydia STACK-MICHASIW Brooke BATES Ella EIDSVIK Elite/Open Men Eric BERG Ryan MACLEAN Manu MOORE U15 Men James CHALKLEY William KINDZIERSKI Finlay ROBERTS U17 Men Ethan WOOD Larix HALLETT Quinten MACKLEM Masters Men 35-44 Andrew DAVIDSON Graham DIEHL Jesse BAUER Masters Men 45-54 Mark KNOLL Paul MARTIN David ROBERTS Masters Men 55-64 Ed GARVIN Peter LAWRENCE Robert MARTENS Masters Men 65+ Gregory PATYCHUK Ken GERMAINE John ATTO Masters Women 35-44 Pepper HARLTON Bridget LINDER Jenn PROCHE Masters Women 45-54 Susanne MCARTHUR Shantel KOENIG Shawna DONALDSON Masters Women 55-64 Rachel DUMONT Junior Men Ben MORIN Colton ZABOLOTNEY Rhett BATES my results Did not race read more </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
