<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aba cx cup on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/aba-cx-cup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aba cx cup on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/aba-cx-cup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>my 2023 season summary</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2023/</guid>
      <description>In 2023 I was hoping to be a better racer. I spent the winter actually using the gym we have at work, doing time on the stationary bike so as not to lose all my kilometres in my legs. They say you should do strength training and I tried but it&amp;rsquo;s a pain.&#xA;The other thing I did was join a club. Velocity Cycling Club is my new bunch. We have a coach and club jerseys and it&amp;rsquo;s all a bit more community-building than the lone-wolf cyclist thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>crossbow semiprestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/crossbow2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/crossbow2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Rutland Park, Calgary Course: stravalink I missed out on writing this up at the end of the 2023 CX season, and now that 2024 has come around, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a bunch of the data I like to put in these race writeups. Nonetheless, here&amp;rsquo;s what I can find (thankfully I did do my CrossResults upload back when the race happened).&#xA;This race was postponed from earlier in the month because of some freakish weather.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>snakes &amp; ladders III 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/snakesladders2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/snakesladders2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Snakes Head Natural Area, Sundre Course: stravalink I missed out on writing this up at the end of the 2023 CX season, and now that 2024 has come around, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a bunch of the data I like to put in these race writeups. Nonetheless, here&amp;rsquo;s what I can find (thankfully I did do my CrossResults upload back when the race happened).&#xA;results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Adam ROBERTS Brendan CARDIFF1 Jason PROCHE Novice Men Cor SINKE William KINDZIERSKI Arun WARD Open Men Mark FAGNAN Andrew DAVIDSON Scott DESMARAIS Open Women Francesca SEAL Susanne MCARTHUR Quinn FLATER Sport Men Josh BARKER Sean SWEENEY Carl MILLER Sport Women Kathryn SWEENEY Hazel ROBERTS Madeline MAGLEO my results did not race read more Velocity Cycling Club woo!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>baby walter cross 2023 - day 2</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-2/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Queen Elizabeth Park Edmonton Course: stravalink I had hoped to do more racing this year, but it turned out that four was what I could handle with my work and other life commitments. So the second day of Baby Walter Cross was my season closer.&#xA;1&#xA;The course this year went the opposite direction of 2022 which I think I preferred. The climbing of the stupid hill was still tough, but the descents weren&amp;rsquo;t terrifying and we got to skip the runup in favour of a singletrack descent (with roots that were highlighted but you needed to dodge).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>baby walter cross 2023 - day 1</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/zombiebabywaltercross2023-1/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Queen Elizabeth Park Edmonton Course: stravalink Baby Walter Cross is a two-day race put on by the Alberta Cyclocross Collective, which isn&amp;rsquo;t a club exactly, just all the cx lovers in Edmonton. The park has a really big hill, which makes for a lot of climbing.&#xA;Apparently on the Saturday race (which I didn&amp;rsquo;t attend) there were some big crashes by people trying to bunny-hop the obstacles and failing badly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>terrascape beans n barley 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/bicicross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/bicicross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Richmond Green Park, Calgary Course: stravalink I missed out on writing this up at the end of the 2023 CX season, and now that 2024 has come around, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a bunch of the data I like to put in these race writeups. Nonetheless, here&amp;rsquo;s what I can find (thankfully I did do my CrossResults upload back when the race happened).&#xA;results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Larix HALLETT Emile VOGEL-NAKAMURA Spencer POOTZ Novice Men Cor SINKE William LEMIEUX Emmet MACKLEM Open Men Eric BERG Ryan MACLEAN Mark FAGNAN Open Women Jenaya FRANCIS Nico KNOLL Francesca SEAL Sport Men Joel DYCK Sean SWEENEY Brendan CARDIFF1 Sport Women Tayte PROULX-ROYDS Hazel ROBERTS Kathryn SWEENEY my results did not race read more Velocity Cycling Club woo!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bicicross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/bicicross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/bicicross2023/</guid>
      <description> Tech Guide Location: Richmond Green Park, Calgary Course: stravalink I missed out on writing this up at the end of the 2023 CX season, and now that 2024 has come around, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a bunch of the data I like to put in these race writeups. Nonetheless, here&amp;rsquo;s what I can find (thankfully I did do my CrossResults upload back when the race happened).&#xA;results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Emile VOGEL-NAKAMURA Larix HALLETT Spencer POOTZ Novice Men William LEMIEUX Carson BROWN Douglas GRAY Open Men Eric BERG Andrew DAVIDSON Mark FAGNAN Open Women Jenaya FRANCIS Nico KNOLL Kelsey DUFFIELD Sport Men Joel DYCK Clarke ELLIS Sean SWEENEY Sport Women Tayte PROULX-ROYDS Kathryn SWEENEY Hazel ROBERTS my results did not race read more </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hardcore hop n hurl 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/hopnhurl2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/hopnhurl2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Voyageur Park Devon Course: stravalink I came into this race knowing that last year&amp;rsquo;s Puncheur Cross was my favourite. Unfortunately I had a training crash the Tuesday before this race, which put me in kind of a bad place. Mostly scraped up, but also a bit of a bruised wrist and some bruised ribs. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d be okay to race still, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t setting my expectations too high.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>drie zussen superprestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</guid>
      <description> Tech Guide Location: Canmore Nordic Centre Canmore Course: stravalink ABA Cup race. Construction on the course. Looked beautiful in the mountains. This is where I&amp;rsquo;d like to go for a travelling race next year.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Open Women Christiane BILODEAU Nico KNOLL Kelsey DUFFIELD Open Men Mark FAGNAN Finn BORSTMAYER Eric BERG Expert Men Jacob PLAYFAIR Larix HALLETT Brett GREINER Novice Men Petr HOLUB Mitchell ROBERTS Emmett MACKLEM Sport Men Patrick MCCRADY Nigel BAINES Sean SWEENEY Sport Women Lydia STACK-MICHASIW Daena SIDNEY Kathryn SWEENEY my results Did not race read more bike stuff </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>school of cross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink Like the previous day&amp;rsquo;s Jim Horner Grand Prix ERTC&amp;rsquo;s School of Cross (p/b Blindman Brewing) 2023 race happened in Capilano Park. The air quality was a bit better on the day so only one race was cancelled (Open Women).&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Elite/Open Men Mark FAGNAN Graham FRANCIS Ryan MCLEAN Expert Men Paulo ALVES 1 Jacob PLAYFAIR Randy PERRY Novice Men Quinten MACKLEM2 Emmett MACKLEM Evan KINDZIERSKI Sport Men Ethan MCGHAN Ryan ARYCHUK Colin WEIR CHABA Sport Women Rachel DUMONT [^3] Kristin BAKER Madeline MAGLEO my results Did not race read more Earned promotion up to Open Men, with his second win (in a row, following JHGP) in Expert.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jim horner grand prix 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink I was so happy this race wasn&amp;rsquo;t taking place in Argyll Park this year. I hated the downhill that someone broke a collarbone on last year and lost so much time on it. Capilano Park was near my house and I could practice on it. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t practice hard enough on wet enough grass, because hoo boy did I not do well on that terrain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the real diehl cyclocross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/peloton2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/peloton2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Canadian Southern Baptist Seminary - Cochrane Course: stravalink &amp;ldquo;The Real Diehl&amp;rdquo; Cyclocross&#xA;Peloton&amp;rsquo;s first CX race they&amp;rsquo;ve put on. Swag included a UCI tire checker.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Scott DESMARAIS Spencer POOTZ Larix HALLETT1 Novice Men Joel DYCK William LEMIEUX Douglas GRAY Open Men Andrew DAVIDSON Shawn BUNNIN Mark KNOLL Open Women Pepper HARLTON Kelsey DUFFIELD Nico KNOLL Sport Men Nigel BAINES Robert MARTENS Garth STOTTS Sport Women Alina CUSTODIO Hazel ROBERTS Elané FERGUSON my results Did not race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>deadgoat supercross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/deadgoat2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/deadgoat2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Canadian Southern Baptist Seminary - Cochrane Course: stravalink1 It looks like this was a hot and windy race.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Expert Men Scott DESMARAIS Emile VOGEL-NAKAMURA Spencer POOTZ Novice Men Joel DYCK Karol SIARKA Quinten MACKLEM Open Men Andrew DAVIDSON Shawn BUNNIN Mark KNOLL Open Women Sidney MCGILL Ella MYERS Nico KNOLL Sport Men Larix HALLETT Patrick MCCRADY Nigel BAINES Sport Women Avree COLLING Hazel ROBERTS Hilary BUCKLEY my results Did not race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>velocity cross 2023 - smoked out</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/velocitycross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Strathcona Science Park Course: stravalink (shared with Tubs on Tubs) Sidney McGill was going to be racing in the Open Men category and I was really excited to see her, and to race in the Novice Men, but by 7am the AQHI was over 10 and no one wanted to get blacklung for a race (also the Alberta Bicycle Association won&amp;rsquo;t let you do anything if the index is over 7).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs supercalifragilisticexpialidocius prestige 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Strathcona Science Park Course: stravalink Tubs on Tubs Supercalifragilisticexpialidocius Prestige was the race that was going to open up the 2023 ABA CX season. And it did for the Novice Men, Sport Men and Sport Women categories, but sadly, the AQHI hit 11 and the afternoon races had to be cancelled (along with the next day&amp;rsquo;s entire Velocity CX Race).&#xA;But I got my race in, and it was really fun!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>preparing for a season</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230829-prepping-a-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230829-prepping-a-season/</guid>
      <description>The Alberta Bicycle Association Cyclo-cross Cup begins this weekend with the Tubs on Tubs race and the Velocity CX and I am excited.&#xA;These races take place at Strathcona Science Park, which is a five minute ride from my house, so it&amp;rsquo;s my closest thing to a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; race and where I do most of my ripping around on grass to practice &amp;lsquo;crossing. The other day I was out there and saw someone else also riding around on the grass and flagged her down.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>go team optimism</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230530-coaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/230530-coaching/</guid>
      <description>I joined a cycling club in 2023 and we have a coach. I have never had a coach before. I haven&amp;rsquo;t ever really done sports (part of why my partner tells me I&amp;rsquo;m not an athlete) so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what a coach is supposed to do. But Kevin seems earnest and nice and is trying so hard to be helpful.&#xA;Before this season&amp;rsquo;s first race he held a racers&amp;rsquo; meeting to go over the course using veloviewer and to talk about tactics and what we should be doing before a race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>bike racing season 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/cxseason2022/</guid>
      <description>I rode cyclocross races in 2022 but they didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like cyclocross. They aren&amp;rsquo;t muddy and cold1. Part of that was due to the boiling frog that we are as a planet but part of that is due to living in Edmonton, where we don&amp;rsquo;t really get shoulder seasons. The abrupt floompf of winter that happened on November 2 starts fatbike season, not a time for racing in mud, like in Europe (or even Victoria, which is where the Canadian nationals are going to be happening in November).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tubs on tubs superduper prestige 2022</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/tubsontubs2022/</guid>
      <description>I returned to cyclocross in 2022, and went back to the same race in the same park. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that makes this a classic or not.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d tested this course beforehand. My house is just across the river from the &amp;ldquo;indestructible Strathcona Science Park&amp;rdquo;1 so this was where I&amp;rsquo;d been riding up and down hills and practicing my off-cambers the week before.&#xA;2&#xA;In the tech guide the organizers had released it looked like the really super-steep downhill I&amp;rsquo;d wiped out on in my practice laps back in 2019 was not part of the course, which I appreciated.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
