<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>library on the dubious monk</title><link>http://localhost:1313/categories/library/</link><description>Recent content in library on the dubious monk</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-ca</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:15:27 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/library/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>thinking about 64 squares</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/250131-64squares/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 09:34:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/250131-64squares/</guid><description>&lt;p>I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to focus a bit this past year. When I come home to a quiet house (four days a week) there are many things I could do. Watch shows, read books, cook interesting meals, go out and spend money being around people. But when I have all those options the tendency I have is to just kind of waste it. To work on that I&amp;rsquo;ve got three main things I&amp;rsquo;m working on filling my time with: bikes, books, and chess.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>winning awards</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/150601-winning-awards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 17:26:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/150601-winning-awards/</guid><description>&lt;p>Around our workplace there&amp;rsquo;s a joke that we should all be putting &amp;ldquo;award-winning librarian&amp;rdquo; in our bios when we show up in the outside world. After all, who is to say that the participation award from your grade 4 track meet isn&amp;rsquo;t what made you the professional you are today?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve totally done it though. I called myself award-winning in the bio for a talk Jason and I gave at the Vancouver Island Library Staff Conference a few weeks ago, because I really did win an award for making radio back in journalism school. It seemed relevant as part of my radio librarian bona fides. But whatever.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>your friendly neighbourhood wretched hive of scum &amp; villainy - a presentation</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/120920-your-friendly-neighbourhood-wretched-hive-of-scum-villainy-a-presentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 04:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/120920-your-friendly-neighbourhood-wretched-hive-of-scum-villainy-a-presentation/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote class='book-hint '>
 &lt;p>This is a slightly modified version of the text (and slides) from my talk at Oh, the Places You&amp;rsquo;ll Know, a part of SFU&amp;rsquo;s Public Square on September 19, 2012. We were encouraged to put practical considerations aside, hence the &amp;ldquo;damn the lawyers; full speed ahead!&amp;rdquo; approach advocated within.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>&lt;p>My big idea for public libraries is that they should embrace the role of &amp;ldquo;Your Friendly Neighbourhood Wretched Hive of Scum and Villainy.&amp;rdquo; To begin, and to situate us here, I agree with &lt;a href="http://www.newlibrarianship.org/" title="The Atlas of New Librarianship">R. David Lankes&lt;/a> when he says &amp;ldquo;the mission of librarians is to facilitate knowledge creation in their communities.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s a great mission, but I think it is very easy for us to mis-define our communities. I want my library (and this is a hypothetical library - I&amp;rsquo;m not representing anyone&amp;rsquo;s views but my own here) to serve the community it&amp;rsquo;s in and not the rules of publishers, movie studios or lawmakers.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>