<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>capilano park on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/capilano-park/</link>
    <description>Recent content in capilano park on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/capilano-park/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>school of cross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink Like the previous day&amp;rsquo;s Jim Horner Grand Prix ERTC&amp;rsquo;s School of Cross (p/b Blindman Brewing) 2023 race happened in Capilano Park. The air quality was a bit better on the day so only one race was cancelled (Open Women).&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Elite/Open Men Mark FAGNAN Graham FRANCIS Ryan MCLEAN Expert Men Paulo ALVES 1 Jacob PLAYFAIR Randy PERRY Novice Men Quinten MACKLEM2 Emmett MACKLEM Evan KINDZIERSKI Sport Men Ethan MCGHAN Ryan ARYCHUK Colin WEIR CHABA Sport Women Rachel DUMONT [^3] Kristin BAKER Madeline MAGLEO my results Did not race read more Earned promotion up to Open Men, with his second win (in a row, following JHGP) in Expert.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jim horner grand prix 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/jimhornergrandprix2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink I was so happy this race wasn&amp;rsquo;t taking place in Argyll Park this year. I hated the downhill that someone broke a collarbone on last year and lost so much time on it. Capilano Park was near my house and I could practice on it. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t practice hard enough on wet enough grass, because hoo boy did I not do well on that terrain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>capilano park</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/capilanopark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/capilanopark/</guid>
      <description>Capilano Park is a park in the city of Edmonton, where I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t actually expect a cx race to work, but it does.&#xA;As far as the singletrack in the park goes, this is where you connect up with Goldbar Park and the cool trails in there. I generally prefer riding Eastbound.&#xA;races Jim Horner Grand Prix 2023 School of Cross 2023 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>midweek racing</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wnw2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wnw2023/</guid>
      <description>As part of my season preparations I decided to at least try the midweek cx racing that goes on in Edmonton. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird because it&amp;rsquo;s so casual and hard to find information about. There are people asking questions in the Alberta CX Facebook group and you get a response with a screenshot from somewhere(?) giving a schedule. It seems that the people who know, know.&#xA;And holy crap did a lot of people know about it last night!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
