<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ftt on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/ftt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ftt on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/ftt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>fat tire tuesday race series</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/ftt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/ftt/</guid>
      <description>Fat Tire Tuesday is a cross-country mountain bike race series in Edmonton. In 2024, all the races are happening at Terwillegar park. The races cost $5 and you can enter in three categories (the fastest do 4 laps, the slower people do 3 laps and the slowest only do 2). There&amp;rsquo;s a point structure and a group on Strava where the news of race results/cancellations happen.&#xA;Further reading of my personal responses with the races can be found under the ftt tag or in my season summaries below:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>my 2024 mtb racing season summary</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/fttseason2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/fttseason2024/</guid>
      <description>For me, mountain bike racing is not something I&amp;rsquo;m super into, so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t pay much to do it like I do cyclocross, but the Fat Tire Tuesday races had always looked like fun so in 2024 I took the plunge.&#xA;Race 1 2024-05-14: stravalink Started off with steep uphill on rocky surface. I got caught behind a couple of riders who went way slower than I could have, putting me in a hole the rest of the race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>spring again</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240425-spring-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 13:26:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/240425-spring-again/</guid>
      <description>It is almost the end of April in 2024 and my Strava account says I&amp;rsquo;m in better shape than I was at any point last year. I&amp;rsquo;ve been out for a couple of VCC rides this season where it&amp;rsquo;s been about 11 degrees and I wore my tights and seemed to fit in pretty well.&#xA;In the first week there was a fast group and a slow group, which I definitely knew I should stick with (Strava number notwithstanding).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
