<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>school of cross on the dubious monk</title>
    <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/school-of-cross/</link>
    <description>Recent content in school of cross on the dubious monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thedubiousmonk.net/tags/school-of-cross/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>school of cross 2024</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2024/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink Part two of the first Edmonton race weekend saw way more people (in my race at least). The course went backwards compared to Jim Horner the previous day. This was good for me because it meant we had a non-technical climb right after the start, and that&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m pretty decent at. It also meant that the switchbacks we&amp;rsquo;d been climbing on Saturday were now a descent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>western cyclocross challenge 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/wccx2023/</guid>
      <description> Tech Guide Location: Canmore Nordic Centre Canmore Course: stravalink Western Challenge CX. This race is done in age groups to get points for call-ups for Nationals and what have you.&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Elite/Open Women Ella MYERS Christiane BILODEAU Francesca SEAL Elite/Open Men Eric BERG Ryan MACLEAN Manu MOORE Junior Women Nico KNOLL Maria MCCARTNEY Keely HAMILTON Junior Men Ben MORIN Colton ZABOLOTNEY Rhett BATES U17 Women Lydia STACK-MICHASIW Brooke BATES Ella EIDSVIK U17 Men Ethan WOOD Larix HALLETT Quinten MACKLEM U15 Women Hazel ROBERTS Eliza MCRAE U15 Men James CHALKLEY William KINDZIERSKI Finlay ROBERTS Masters Women 35-44 Pepper HARLTON Bridget LINDER Jenn PROCHE Masters Men 35-44 Andrew DAVIDSON Graham DIEHL Jesse BAUER Masters Women 45-54 Susanne MCARTHUR Shantel KOENIG Shawna DONALDSON Masters Men 45-54 Mark KNOLL Paul MARTIN David ROBERTS Masters Women 55-64 Rachel DUMONT Masters Men 55-64 Ed GARVIN Peter LAWRENCE Robert MARTENS Masters Men 65+ Gregory PATYCHUK Ken GERMAINE John ATTO my results Did not race read more Drie Zussen Superprestige 2023 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>school of cross 2023</title>
      <link>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thedubiousmonk.net/posts/schoolofcross2023/</guid>
      <description>Tech Guide Location: Capilano Park Edmonton Course: stravalink Like the previous day&amp;rsquo;s Jim Horner Grand Prix ERTC&amp;rsquo;s School of Cross (p/b Blindman Brewing) 2023 race happened in Capilano Park. The air quality was a bit better on the day so only one race was cancelled (Open Women).&#xA;results ABA Results CrossResults Podia Open Men Mark FAGNAN Graham FRANCIS Ryan MCLEAN Expert Men Paulo ALVES 1 Jacob PLAYFAIR Randy PERRY Sport Women Rachel DUMONT [^3] Kristin BAKER Madeline MAGLEO Sport Men Ethan MCGHAN Ryan ARYCHUK Colin WEIR CHABA Novice Men Quinten MACKLEM2 Emmett MACKLEM Evan KINDZIERSKI my results Did not race read more Earned promotion up to Open Men, with his second win (in a row, following JHGP) in Expert.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
